-嗨，艾迪        -嗨，史考特
-Hy, Eddie.      -Hiya, Scotty.
-夠冷了吧？   -我只是一息尚存，零下25度
-Cold enough for you?   -Well, I'm only faintly alive. It's 25 below.
-每個人都認識嗎？    -我們還沒見過面
-You know everybody?    -We haven't met.
-麥克弗森          -嗨
-McPherson.     -Hi.
奈德.史考特，亨德利隊長  史考特今天剛到
Ned Scott, Capt. Hendry. Scotty just got in today.
嗨，加入我們如何？
Hi, care to join us?
等我數一數手指頭。我可能掉了一根
Wait till I count my fingers. I may have lost one.
史考特喜歡溫暖氣候，我們在阿克拉碰面
好個地點，陰影下有105度...
Scotty's a warm-weather man. We met at Accra. Quite a spot. 105 in the shade...
...女人幾乎沒穿衣服，她們非常聰明
...and the women hardly wore anything at all. Very intelligent of them.
三個妞幫你搧涼，你只管躺在吊床上
You just lie there in a hammock while three of them fan you.
-記得嗎，史考特？       -我記得
-Remember, Scotty?     -I remember.
-好傢伙。希望死前能去阿克拉  -我去過了
-Oh, boy. When I die I hope I go to Accra.   -I was there.
我跟
I'm in.
史考特先生，你來這幹嘛？  -找報導題材
-What are you doing here, Mr. Scott?   -Looking for a story.
史考特是一名記者
Scotty's a newspaperman.
-幾張？         -三張
-How many?    -Three.
-玩牌？       -我會玩這些
-Cards?      -I'll play these.
-中計了            -驗牌
-Caught from ambush.    -Check.
-下注一塊錢        -我要封牌
-Well, I'll bet a buck.    -And I'll fold.
叫牌
Call.
-皇后一對        -我想也是，老A
-Pair of queens.    -I thought so. Aces.
你應該知道不該愚弄我們的隊長，除非是女人
You ought to know better than to try fooling our captain. Only dames can do that.
-戴克斯中尉，我保證...    -說溜了嘴
-Lt. Dykes, I promise...   -Slip of the tongue.
-將軍那兒有新聞嗎？ -福格蒂的秘書像個六月新娘
-What do you hear from the general?
-Fogarty's nursing secrets like a June bride.
我有個主意。西雅圖有個人知道雷達防禦內幕...
I got an idea. A guy in Seattle knows a whole radar defense story...
...很想談談，就是麥克連將軍
...loves to talk. General McLaren.
告訴福格蒂將軍你想去西雅圖，帕特和我會載你去
Tell General Fogarty you want to go to Seattle, and Pat and I will fly you there.
我也見過麥克連將軍了
I met General McLaren too.
西雅圖很溫暖，那裡的女孩不皮褲的
It's warm in Seattle. They got girls there without fur pants on.
-隊長，怎麼樣？      -應該可行
-What about it, captain?    -That could be right.
你別想哄我們的隊長往南走...
You won't be able to shoo our captain southward with his heart...
...當他心繫北極時     -適可而止
...wrapped around the North Pole.   -That'll do.
-那裡有什麼事？ -科學家要召開一次會議
-What's going on up there?   -Scientists are holding a convention.
-尋找北極熊的尾巴  -有聽過卡林頓博士？
-Looking for polar bear tails.   -Ever hear of Dr. Carrington?
-比基尼的那傢伙？     -就是他
-The fellow who was at Bikini?   -The same.
他們離這裡北方約兩千英里處，一整群
They're holding about 2000 miles north of here. A whole bunch.
-植物學家 物理學家 電子...  -包括一個美女
-Botanists, physicists, electronic...  -Including a pin-up girl.
-非常有趣的類型     -非常
-Very interesting type too.     -Very.
亨德利隊長可以提供關於她的所有資訊
Capt. Hendry can give you any data on her.
-或許你不該說那些      -等我讀完...
-You probably shouldn't have said that.   -Well, after I read...
現在看！
Now look!
希望有一天，我有導航員和副駕駛各一
至少他們的耳後是乾的
Someday I hope to have a navigator and a copilot who are at least dry behind the ears.
-哦，隊長         -你郵購...
-Oh, captain.    -You mail-order...
亨德利隊長，請立即去福格蒂將軍的宿舍報到
Capt. Hendry, report to General Fogarty's quarters at once please.
晚上8點，將軍對部隊大吼大叫，像是回到從前
8:00 at night and the general yelling for his troops. Sounds like the old days.
-替一下手 好嗎？       -好啊
-Take my hand. Will you?    -Yeah.
隊長，如果有任何差事，帶我去。拜託？
Captain, if it amounts to anything,
bring me in on it. Will you, please?
當然。
Sure.
我得去某個地方找新聞
I gotta get a story someplace.
進來吧
Come in.
-關上門         -是的，長官
-Close the door.     -Yes, sir.
-晚安，長官        -你很快就來了
-Good evening, sir.   -Didn't take you long.
長官，我沒地方可躲啊
Not many places to hide, sir.
剛得自北方一則奇怪的信息，卡林頓博士親自發送
Just got a queer message from your picnic party up north,
from Dr. Carrington himself.
“據信有一架怪異機型的飛機在我方附近墜毀
"Believe an airplane unusual type crashed in our vicinity.
請派員進行調查，十萬火急“
Please send facilities to investigate. Most urgent."
除了一個美女之外，你認為還能發現什麼？
What do supose you find up there besides a good-Iooking girl?
-我不知道，長官，有船失蹤嗎？   -沒有
-I don't know, sir. Any ships missing?   -No.
-也沒有加拿大人     -可能是俄羅斯人
-No Canadians either.    -Could be Russians.
-他們像蒼蠅一樣遍布極地    -你出發吧
-They're all over the pole like flies.   -You're going.
-帶一隊狗或其他救援設備     -是，長官
-Take along a dog team or anything you might need for rescue.  -Yes Sir
進來吧
Come in.
如果你這次沒砸壞起落架，我會很高興
I'd like it if you didn't smash into the landing ski this time.
那次是無法避免的意外
That was an unavoidable accident.
嘿，我希望你明天晚上能回來
Look, I'll expect you back sometime tomorrow night.
-是，長官。我會帶上門   -告訴我發現了什麼
-Yes, sir. And I'll close the door.
-Just tell me what you find up there.
這兒再也沒有人跟我報告事情了
No one tells me anything around here.
要咖啡嗎？
Want some coffee?
-嘿，謝謝       -這給你，長官
-Hey, thanks.    -Here you are, sir.
史考特先生，咖啡
Mr. Scott. Coffee.
-到了嗎？      -不，先生。熱咖啡
-Are we there?   -No, sir. Hot coffee up front, sir.
-中尉？咖啡，長官     -謝謝你，空服員
-Lieutenant? Coffee, sir.   -Thank you, stewardess.
-咖啡？          -好，謝謝
-Coffee?     -Yeah, thanks.
離營地還有多遠？
How far are we from camp?
三個小時。我們慢下來了，有點逆風
Three hours. We've slowed down. A little headwind.
有點？風速將近40英里
A little headwind? Close to 40 miles.
我們隊長對北極有一些有趣的看法
Our captain has some funny ideas about the North Pole.
他認為這是一個花園景點，快帶小孩來吧
He thinks it's a garden spot. Come and bring the kiddies.
嘿，你們兩個不要鬧了
Now look, don't you two guys start.
你知道，佩里曾去過北極，得了一大堆獎章退休
You know, Perry went to the North Pole once.
He retired with a sack full of medals.
嘿，帕特
Hey, Pat.
我們每隔三個星期去一趟，就像是幽會車道
We go there every three weeks just like it was lover's lane.
史考特先生，有人似乎想...等一下
Mr. Scott, some people seem to think... Wait a minute.
來自極地探險6隊的空軍191，有收到嗎？
Hello, Air Force 191 from Polar Expedition 6. Can you read me?
空軍191，很清楚，特克斯。繼續
Air Force 191. Hear you fine, Tex. Go ahead.
-你的位置在哪裡？     -三小時之外
-What's your position?   -Three hours out.
隊長，切到無線電羅盤，檢查磁航向
Captain, switch over to your radio compass.
Check it against your magnetic heading.
有問題嗎，特克斯？
What's on your mind, Tex?
我們這裡有一些干擾，全部都被搞亂了
We've got some disturbance up here. It's whacking away at everything.
-你覺得干擾源在哪裡？  -不知道，昨晚才注意
-What do you figure it's from?
-Don't know. We noticed it last night.
-六到八度的誤差  -這裡差相當多，特克斯
-Six to eight degrees difference.
-We're quite a bit off here, Tex.
你最好隨時注意我，我會保持開機
You better home in on me. I'll leave the key open.
-或者你寧願我用唱的？    -保持開機吧
-Or would you rather have me sing to you?   -Leave the key open.
我就怕你會這樣說
I was afraid you'd say that.
嘿，納稅人應該來看看
Hey, the taxpayers ought to see this.
你好，博士，教授
Hello, doctor, professor.
-還是老牌局？      -是啊
-Still the same game?    -Yes.
嗨，小子們
Hello, boys.
-博士，教授。你的信件  -你正好趕上午餐
-Doctor, professor. Here's your mail.
-You're just in time for lunch.
-肯，你一定忘了我的髮夾  -別跟我說到北極了
-Ken, I bet you forgot my hairpins.
-Don't tell me I'm nearly at the North Pole.
-很像肯塔基老家  -史考特先生，查普曼太太
-Looks more like my Kentucky home.   -Mr. Scott, Mrs. Chapman.
-很榮幸，查普曼夫人   -嗨，幸會了
-A pleasure, Mrs. Chapman.   -Hi, nice to see you.
-查普曼博士，史考特先生  -查普曼博士
-Dr. Chapman, Mr. Scott.   -Dr. Chapman.
-史考特是一名記者   -你來的正是時候
-Scotty's a newspaperman.   -You've come at an opportune time.
消息傳到時 我碰巧在安克拉治 希望你有好故事
I happened to be in Anchorage when your message came.
I hope you have a good story.
-不會比你知道的還多    -什麼都沒有？
-No more than you know already.   -Nothing more at all?
只是討論它可能是什麼，大家的想法分歧
Just discussions as to what it might be.
We all have different ideas.
-還有一些爭議    -卡林頓博士在哪兒？
-There's been arguments about it.
-Where's Dr. Carrington?
-在實驗室       -回頭見
-In the lab.      -See you later.
這麼說...你看過這架飛機嗎？
Does that mean you've seen the plane?
-咖啡，隊長？       -不用了，謝謝
-Coffee, captain?     -No, thanks.
李，我們的隊長似乎很匆忙
Our captain seems in a hurry, Lee.
-你們兩個要去哪？   -跟你一起去
-Where are you two going?    -We're with you.
-我們想去質疑她對你不好  -如果不要我們...
-We want to tell her she treated you badly.
-If you don't want us to go...
-改天再跟你們算帳    -我們在那裡起床
-I'm gonna get even with you two someday.   -We got up in there.
進來吧
Come in.
嗨，帕特。歡迎來到我們的冰屋。你好嗎...？
Hi, Pat. Welcome to our igloo. How was your...?
呃...
Well...
-旅途愉快吧？      -跟平常一樣
-How was your trip?   -All right. About usual.
嗯，那就好
Well, that's fine.
-卡林頓博士想見你  -他不急，我想和你談
-I think Dr. Carrington wants to see you.
-He can wait. I wanna talk to you.
-關於什麼？   -就是你玩的骯髒伎倆
-What about?   -That was a dirty trick you played.
-別發脾氣   -為何那麼做？告訴我為什麼
-Don't lose your temper.
-Why did you do it? Just tell me why.
你的腿不是很漂亮
Well, your legs aren't very pretty.
你沒必要寫一張便條 放在我的胸前
You didn't have to write a note and put it on my chest.
對不起，帕特...
I'm sorry, Pat...
我醒來之前 有六個人看過 現在全空軍皆知了
Six people read it before I woke up.
Now the whole Air Force knows.
-別那麼大聲，別人會聽見  -他們都聽過了
-Not so loud. They'll hear.   -They already heard.
只差沒在公佈欄公告而已
The only place it hasn't been is on a billboard.
我不知道你有這麼討厭的脾氣
I didn't know you had such a nasty temper.
帕特，請息怒。放輕鬆一點
Now, Pat, just be careful. Now take it easy.
等一等
Now wait a minute.
上次你來這裡時，我們玩得很開心
We had a lot of fun when you were up here.
然後當你邀我去安克拉治時，你故意餵我...
Then when you asked me down to Anchorage, you deliberately fed me...
告訴我，你真的把那些飲料全喝了嗎？
Tell me, did you really drink all those drinks?
-你沒扔掉任何東西？一個都沒有？ -沒有
-You didn't throw any away? Not one?   -No.
老天，我還以為我很棒
Holy cat. I thought I was good.
還有一件事，你為什麼要走？
And another thing, why did you leave?
當我早上醒來時你已經走了
When I woke up in the morning you were gone.
我告訴過你 我必須把那架貨機帶回來
I told you I had to take that cargo plane back here.
-你告訴過我？   -你不記得嗎？
-You told me?   -Don't you remember?
不
No.
晚餐後，你告訴我關於在舊金山的某晚...
Right after dinner. You were telling me all about a night in San Francisco...
我告訴過你那個？
Did I tell you that?
我還做了什麼？
What else did I do?
曾有一度你有點像一隻章魚。
Well, you had moments of kind of making like an octopus.
-我一生中未曾見過這麼多手   -好了，好了
-I never saw so many hands in all my life.
-All right. All right.
嘿，我唯一的藉口是我喜歡你...
Look, my only excuse is that I liked you...
...立刻的
...right away.
-原來是錯誤的開始，不能重來嗎？  -你要怎樣開始？
-So I started wrong. Can't we begin again?
-How would you begin?
-我能想到幾個...     -別麻煩了
-Well, I can think of several...   -Never mind.
無論如何，我們現在沒那時間
We don't have time for that now anyway.
我知道卡林頓博士正等著見你
I know Dr. Carrington's waiting to see you.
-重新開始要怎麼辦？   -稍後再談吧
-What about this business of starting over?
-We'll talk about that later.
-你好，隊長       -嗨，教授
-Hello, captain.    -Hi, professor.
-卡林頓博士，亨德利隊長來了  -我知道
-Dr. Carrington, Capt. Hendry is here.   -Yes, I know.
久仰了，隊長？      -博士
-How do you do, captain?    -Doctor.
尼克森小姐，你能在筆記上添上一則嗎？
Miss Nicholson, would you add a note to the others?
當然
Surely.
11月2日 上午11:30
November 2, 11:30 a.m.
第19區的偏差持續向東12度20分
Deviation in sector 19 continues 12 degrees, 20 minutes east.
干擾因素沒有減少或搖擺不定
No lessening or wavering of disturbing element.
就這樣
That's all.
-隊長，可以開始了嗎？  -該往哪裡走？
-Captain, can we start now?
-Mind telling me where we're going?
由此往東48英里
48 miles due east from here.
你的消息說飛機墜毀了，我們要去找嗎？
Your message said an airplane crashed.
Is that what we're looking for?
我不知道，隊長
I don't know, captain.
-你最好解釋一下      -對不起
-I think you better explain.    -I'm sorry.
尼克森小姐，能宣讀我的第一次筆記嗎？
Miss Nicholson, would you read Capt. Hendry my first notes?
我才在想我的信息含糊不清，我不喜歡含糊
I was thinking only of the vagueness of my information. I dislike being vague.
-"11月1日...         -昨天
-"November 1st...    -Yesterday.
...下午6:15探聲器和地震儀顯示東方有爆炸
...6:15 p.m. Sound detectors and seismographs registered explosion due east.
在6點18分，磁力計顯示向東偏離12度20分"
At 6:18, magnetometer revealed deviation 12 degrees, 20 minutes east."
-偏差一直恆定   -我們到達之前也遇上了
-That deviation has been constant.
-We ran into it before we got here.
“這種偏差只有一種可能：干擾力要相當於...
"Such deviation possible only if a disturbing force equivalent...
...兩萬噸的鋼鐵或鐵礦石...   -兩萬噸？
...to 20,000 tons of steel or iron ore...
-20,000 tons?
...已成為地球的一部分 約有半徑50英里"
...had become part of the earth at about a 50-mile radius."
我有點無法理解，但聽起來像一顆隕石
You're getting a bit beyond me, but it sounds like a meteor.
是的，很像。除了一件事
Yes, very much. Except for one thing.
-展示給亨德利隊長看    -是，先生
-Will, show it to Capt. Hendry.   -Yes, sir.
我們有一些特殊的望遠鏡相機
We have some special telescopic cameras.
用於放射性的顯像，兼具蓋革偵測器...
On the appearance of radioactivity, a Geiger counter trips the release...
...和相機功能
...and the cameras function.
他們昨晚進行了，結果在這裡
They were working last evening. This is the result.
第一張照片是在爆炸前三分鐘拍攝的...
This first picture was taken three minutes before the explosion...
...或是說6點12分
...or 6:12.
你可以看到下方角落的小點
You can see the small dot below there in the corner.
而下一張照片，一分鐘後，那個點由西往東移動...
On the next picture, one minute later,
that dot is moving from west to east...
...快得能形成一條線   -快門是多少？
...fast enough to form a streak.   -What shutter speed is it?
-千分之一秒     -相當快，對吧？
-1000th of a second.   -Moving pretty fast. Wasn't it?
這裡，在6點14分，它向上移動
Here, at 6:14, it's moving upward.
6:15，掉落地面消失了
6:15, it drops to the earth and vanishes.
流星能近乎水平向地球移動，但從不向上
A meteor might move almost horizontal to the earth but never upward.
-那就不是流星      -很明顯不是
-Then it isn't a meteor.   -That's obvious.
你怎麼發現撞擊的距離？
How'd you find the distance of impact?
-通過計算...       -卡林頓博士？
-By computation...    -Dr. Carrington?
-好了嗎？      -隊長，很簡單
-Ready?    -It's quite simple, captain.
我們有聲波到達的時間和探測器
We have the time of arrival of the sound waves and detectors.
還有地震儀上衝擊波的到達時間
And also the arrival time of the impact waves on the seismograph.
計算時間差，是那個物體造成得沒錯
By computing the difference, it becomes obvious they were caused by the object.
-距離這裡48英里    -就依你說的
-The distance from here is 48 miles.
-I'll take your word for it.
有一點，2萬噸鋼對飛機來說分量不輕啊
One thing, doctor. 20,000 tons of steel is a lot of metal for an airplane.
這是對我們所了解的那種飛機而言，隊長
It is for the sort of airplane we know, captain.
-我們該走了  -雷丁會每隔一刻檢查一次
-Yeah, we'd better be going.
-Redding will check every quarter-hour.
-博士，需要我嗎？    -沒這必要
-Will you want me, doctor?   -It won't be necessary.
比爾，你和我們走      -是，博士
-You come with us, Bill.    -Yes, doctor.
帕特，我們很快就會到
We'll be there pretty soon now, Pat.
鮑伯，叫卡林頓來這裡。
Bob, get Carrington up here.
博士！
Doctor!
博士，差不多在50英里之外了
We're almost 50 miles out, doctor.
羅盤有偏差，你要如何導航，隊長？
With your compass deviation, how are you navigating, captain?
前面的山峰實際上是正東方向
That peak ahead is practically due east.
在離開營地之前，我們抓到了氣流*
We got the wind before we left camp.
-非常好，隊長   -現在應該到達了，帕特
-Very good, captain.   -We should be there about now, Pat.
十。九。八。七。六。
Ten. Nine. Eight. Seven. Six.
長官，蓋革偵測器有讀數了
Picking up something on the Geiger counter, sir.
五。四。三。二。一。
Five. Four. Three. Two. One.
看這裡
Look there.
-帕特，羅盤亂轉   -蓋革偵測器破表
-Pat, the compass is in a spin.   -Geiger's up to the top.
是的，就是這樣，沒錯
Yeah, that's it, all right.
-有降落點嗎？   -後方半英里似乎平滑
-You see someplace to set down?
-Looked smooth about a half a mile back.
我們瞧瞧。鮑伯！叫大家預備，可能很顛簸
We'll take a look. Bob! Get them ready. It might be rough.
好，長官
Right, sir.
大家繫好安全帶，要降落了
Fasten your seat belts, gentlemen. We're gonna land.
後面的坐下來抓牢
Sit down and hold on back there.
長官，準備著陸就緒
All set for landing, sir.
半襟翼
Half flaps.
-全富油        -全富油*
-Full rich.     -Full rich.
半襟翼
Half flaps.
我們到了
There we are.
老天！好怪異的景象
Holy cat! What a weird-Iooking thing.
在你們佈滿足跡之前 先讓我拍照
Let me get a picture before you track up the whole place.
這個蓋革偵測器瘋了
This Geiger counter is going crazy.
有東西溶解了外殼，又被透明的冰凍結了
Something's melted that surface crust.
It's frozen over again into clear ice.
顯然是飛行體第一次在瓶頸處撞擊地球時...
The bottle shape apparently was caused by the craft first making contact...
...而形成這個瓶子的造型...
...with the earth out at the neck of the bottle...
...向我方滑動，在停止之前形成較大的區域
...sliding toward us and forming that larger area as it came to rest.
發動機產生足夠的熱量 融化滑動路徑的冰...
With the engines generating enough heat to melt that path through the crust...
...然後沉入冰層下  -怎麼融化那麼多冰？
...then sink beneath the surface.
-What could melt that much ice?
我們下去看看...巴恩斯
Let's go down and see. Barnes.
把狗帶去那邊
Take the dogs over on that side.
查普曼博士，飛機能融化那麼多冰嗎？
Dr. Chapman, could an airplane melt that much ice?
我們的一架噴射飛機產生的熱量
足以提供50層的辦公大樓的熱氣
One of our own jets generates enough heat to warm a 50-story office building.
-這是機舵的一部分，可能是水平尾翼
-這是一架飛機沒錯
-It's part of an airfoil. Probably a stabilizer.
-It's an airplane, all right.
-說得出這是什麼金屬嗎？  -我需要一些工具
-Can you tell what metal that is?   -I'll need some tools.
巴恩斯，帶一些工具來！
Barnes, bring some tools!
嘿，下沉的很深。烏黑黑的看不出是啥東西
Hey, it's down pretty deep over here.
I can't see anything but a dark mass.
這裡更深
It's deeper over here.
隊長，我們散開來丈量尺寸和確定形狀
Captain, may I suggest that we spread out and try to determine the size and shape.
好，大家散開！想辦法找出這東西的形狀
Right. Spread out, everybody!
We're gonna try to figure out the shape of this thing.
長官，工具來了
Here's the tools, sir.
老天！
Holy cat!
嘿...
Hey...
這幾乎是...
It's almost...
是啊。幾乎是正...
Yeah. Almost a perfect...
是的。是正圓型
It is. It's round.
-終於碰到了一個    -我們發現一個飛碟！
-We finally got one.   -We found a flying saucer!
有誰能透過冰層看到東西嗎？
Can anybody see anything through the ice?
-只有大概的形狀    -只是黑壓壓一團
-Only an outline.   -Nothing but a dark shape.
看起來相當平滑，沒有門窗
Seems perfectly smooth. No doors or windows.
-我沒看到引擎   -我懷疑能找出所謂的引擎
-I can't see any engine.
-I doubt we find anything we call an engine.
卡林頓博士，這不是我所熟知的金屬
Dr. Carrington, this isn't any metal I know.
可能是一些新合金
Probably some new alloy.
-取一些樣品進行分析       -對
-Get some filings for analysis.   -Right.
隊長，我不認為我們能用斧頭來破冰
Captain, I don't think we have a chance of chopping through the ice with axes.
我們有同感。我們將嘗試用鋁熱炸彈來熔冰
I know. We think so too.
We'll try to melt it out with thermite bombs.
-哦，非常好    -你認為它來自哪裡？
-Oh, excellent.   -Where do you figure it's from?
史考特先生，我不知道
I don't know, Mr. Scott.
-來自本星球？    -我對此表示懷疑
-Well, from this planet?   -I doubt it.
-那你呢...？      -答案要等...
-Well, do you...?   -The answers will be much easier...
...我們檢查了飛機的內部...
...after we've examined the interior of the aircraft...
...及其主人，如果還在的話   -主人？我從不...
...and its occupants, if there are any.
-Occupants? Why, I never...
大新聞！哪裡有無線電？嘿，巴恩斯！
What a story! Where's the radio? Hey, Barnes!
-等等，不准私人通信     -"私人"是啥意思？
-Hold it. No private messages.   -What do you mean private?
-我要向全世界發送    -這屬於空軍的消息
-I'm sending it to the whole world.
-This is Air Force information.
等授權下來，你才能發
We'll have to wait for authority to let you file it.
憲法已經授權給你了！這叫做新聞自由
You got your authority in the Constitution!
It's called freedom of the press.
-我要發送一則新聞！  -不能用我們的船
-I'm sending a story!    -Not from our ship.
-炸彈要擺哪裡？   -一個放在水平尾翼...
-Where do you want the bombs?  -One by the stabilizer...
如果有需要的話，另一個放在另一邊
...another over in the far side if we need it.
這是紅海分離以來最大的事件，你隱藏不了的！
It's the biggest story since the parting of the Red Sea. You can't hide it!
-想想這對世界意義重大   -我不是替世界工作
-Think what it means to the world.
-I don't work for the world.
-看...     -不，史考特。我來拿
-Look...   -No, Scott. I'll take that.
-這是信管      -回去船上，呼叫營地
-Here's the detonator.
-Get back to the ship and call the camp.
要特克斯發信，我們在冰上發現了一個飛碟
正試著取出來
Have Tex radio we've found a flying saucer in the ice.
We're gonna try to get it out.
-那我呢？    -也問問史考特能否發送新聞
-What about me?   -Also, ask if Scott can send his story.
-只能幫到這    -你會升官變另一個福格蒂
-That's all I can do.
-You're gonna grow up to be another Fogarty.
-要在哪兒引爆？      -在那邊
-Where we gonna touch this off?   -Over there.
看到西邊了嗎？那鋒面快速移動...
Have you looked to the west? That front's moving fast...
...氣溫也在下降     -我們只剩不到一小時
...and the temperature's dropping too.
-We don't have more than an hour.
鮑伯，那些你放哪裡？    -表面正上方
-Where do you put those, Bob?   -Right on the surface.
-告訴史東，好嗎長官？     -好
-Tell Stone. Will you, sir?    -Right.
嘿，鋁熱彈有什麼用途？
Say, what will this thermite do?
這是S-O-P，用於融冰的標準操作程序
This is S-O-P, standard operating procedure for removing ice.
勾住這根電線，好嗎中尉？只是用來融冰
Hook this wire up, will you, lieutenant? It just melts it.
作用的速度有多快？
How fast does it work?
在30秒內除掉飛碟上方的冰層
It'll uncover the whole saucer in 30 seconds.
-這裡準備好了！     -馬上過去！
-All ready over here!   -Be right with you!
最好清場！直到靠近狗橇附近！一分鐘後會變得很熱
Better clear the field! Over near the dog sled!.
Gonna get pretty hot here in a minute.
勾起來，先試試尾翼 有需要再使用另一個
Hook her up. We'll try the stabilizer first.
Use the other one if we need it.
現在起幾分鐘後，就可能擁有星空之鑰
A few minutes from now we may have the key to the stars.
一百萬年的歷史正在冰下等待著我們
A million years of history are waiting for us in that ice.
-通知一聲，我想拍張照  -長官，就緒了
-Say when. I wanna get a picture.   -All ready, sir.
-這裡就緒了        -引爆吧，鮑伯
-Ready here.    -Let her go, Bob.
-好，清場完畢     -等一下，大家後退
-Okay, all clear.   -Wait a minute, everybody. Stay back.
-它在冰下燃燒       -小心，隊長
-It's burning under the ice.   -Careful, captain.
發生什麼事？
What's happening?
告訴我，博士
Tell me, doctor.
大家趴下！
Get down on the ground, everybody!
大家都好嗎？
Everybody all right?
最後一次爆炸是發動機
That last explosion was the engine.
士官，試一試蓋革計數器好嗎？
Sergeant, will you try your Geiger counter?
-只有一格         -只是殘留物
-Only a trace.   -That's just residual.
全都完了
It's all gone.
可能給我們帶來新科學的秘密
Secrets that might have given us a new science.
-完了       -中看不重用
-Gone.     -That's just dandy.
標準作業程序
Standard operating procedure.
-我應該想到...       -你的確應該
-I should've thought...   -You sure should.
歷史上最偉大的發現 化成火焰
Greatest discovery in history up in flames.
把一個新文明變成國慶焰火
Turning a new civilization into a 4th of July piece.
隊長，我發現這裡有一些東西
Captain, I'm getting something over here.
-可能是飛碟的碎片    -也許還能挽救一些
-Probably a fragment from the saucer.
-We may salvage something yet.
大家別動。有反應了
Hold it, everybody. I'm getting a reaction.
讓我看看讀數
Let me get a reading.
靠近了
Getting warm.
更近了
Hotter now.
這裡是來源
Here's where it's coming from.
-那是什麼？     -看起來像個男人
-What is it?    -Looks like a man.
有腿和頭，我都看得到
It's got legs and a head. I can see them.
是啊！他一定超過8英尺高
Yeah! He must be over 8 feet long.
-有人逃出飛碟     -或是被拋出來的
-Somebody got out of that saucer.   -Or was thrown out.
在他掙脫之前 又被快速凍結
And frozen fast before he could get clear.
-火星人    -你要怎麼弄他出來？
-Man from Mars.   -How do you propose getting him out?
-我不知道     -用更多的鋁熱劑
-I don't know.    -Use more thermite.
反正這是最快的方法，我們沒太多時間
Whatever's quickest. We don't have much time.
用斧頭，沿著邊敲下來 連冰帶人放上飛機
Here's axes. You could chop around and put the block on the plane.
-我同意          -開始吧
-I agree.     -Get started.
-讓開位子    -鮑伯，清理雪橇後帶過來
-Give me room.   -Bob, clear the sled and bring it over here.
艾迪，先去暖機
Eddie, get the ship warmed up.
並準備好趕緊離開這裡
And be ready to get out of here in a hurry.
-帕特，我想我們犯了一個錯誤   -你是說？
-Pat, I think we made a mistake.   -What do you mean?
你看過這篇嗎？“國防部，新聞辦公室
You ever read this?
"Department of Defense, Office of Public Information.
華盛頓特區，1949年12月27日
Washington, D.C. December 27, 1949.
629-49公告 有關於第6700項...
Bulletin 629-49 regarding item 6700...
...75,131號摘錄
...extract 75,131.
空軍已終止飛碟的調查和評估報告...
The Air Force has discontinued investigating and evaluating reported flying saucers...
...基於沒有證據"
...on the basis that there is no evidence."
你銷毀了能證明他們是錯的證據 可能會升上將軍
Probably make you a general for destroying evidence that they're wrong.
“空軍表示，所有證據顯示...
"The Air Force said that all evidence indicates that the reports...
...不明飛行物的報告 結果如下：
...of unidentified flying objects are the result of:
一：對各種傳統物體的誤判"
One: Misinterpretation of various conventional objects."
對我來說 看起來不是很傳統
Didn't look very conventional to me.
"第二：一種輕型的大規模歇斯底里症狀”
"Second: A mild form of mass hysteria."
那是指福格蒂將軍在冰裡與那東西握手的時候
That'd be when General Fogarty got to shaking hands with that thing in the ice.
還有什麼其他原因？
What are the other reasons?
"第三：他們在開玩笑"
"Third: That they're jokes."
你說那個公告是第幾號？
What did you say the number of that bulletin was?
“629-49，第6700項，75,131號摘錄"
"629-49, item 6700, extract 75,131."
哦。哦，那個呀
Oh. Oh, that one.
-教授，抓住繩子    -這裡需要幫手
-Get on that rope, professor.   -I need a hand over here.
小心腳
Watch your feet.
讓我綁上另一條繩子
Let me tie another rope to go down.
-穩住！      -往回拉
-Hold it!     -Hold it back now.
穩住！
Hold it!
拉，回到那裡！
Pull, back there!
抓牢那些繩索！
Keep tight on those ropes!
-輕點          -行了
-Easy.      -Here we go.
-繼續走         -繼續走！
-Keep it going.      -Keep it going!
哇！輕一點
Whoa! Take it easy.
隔著冰看不清楚
Can't see through the ice too good.
知道他來自何方就夠了，長得夠醜的了
Good enough to know that where he came from, they don't breed them for beauty.
現在怎麼辦，把他解凍？
Well, what do we do now, defrost him?
這塊冰很快就會融化
This ice will melt pretty soon.
-能控制這房間的熱度嗎？  -不，這是儲藏室
-Can you control the heat in this room?
-No, captain. This is our storeroom.
這裡要保持恆溫
The temperature's constant here.
我們不用融化它，可以鑿開來
We don't need to melt it. We can chip it away.
我們不會融化或鑿開它。艾迪，打開那扇窗
We're not going to melt it or chip it. Eddie, open that window.
-我們不被允許檢驗它？    -正是此意
-We're not allowed to examine it?   -I mean just that.
-這是愚蠢的      -我們是科學家。
-This is stupid.    -We're scientists.
-這裡由卡林頓博士負責  -帕特，窗戶打不開
-And Dr. Carrington's in charge here.
-Hey, Pat, these windows don't open.
極有可能你的上司會要求我們去研究它
It's practically certain we'll be asked by your superiors to study it.
-也許吧，但現在不行   -我們不需要許可...
-Probably, but we can't permit it now.
-We don't need permission...
-艾迪，打破窗戶       -好
-Eddie, break that window.    -All right.
抱歉。我們剛從冰裡拉起一個尷尬的東西
Sorry. We already pulled one boner out in the ice.
我們可能對此一無所知...
We may not know anything about this...
...但收到上級的指示之前，我們必須緩緩
...but until I receive instructions from my superior officer, we'll have to mark time.
-你沒有權力...   -你想談，就去走廊談
-You have no authority...
-lf you want to talk, do it in the corridor.
-這裡會變冷   -至少這個建議不錯，隊長
-It's gonna get cold in here.
-At last a sensible suggestion, captain.
-麥克           -啥事？
-Mac.        -Yeah?
請留下來，每四小時輪班
Please stay here. And take four-hour shifts.
-大家分勞      -是的，長官
-It's hands off for everyone.   -Yes, sir.
-夠暖嗎？   -如果沒有，就會聽到我尖叫
-Gonna be warm enough?   -If not, you'll hear me squawk.
-鮑伯會送晚餐來    -我可以找些東西來閱讀
-Bob will bring you dinner.   -I could use something to read.
-一個美好，安靜的恐怖故事  -對你來說可能太平淡了
-A nice, quiet horror story.   -Might be kind of tame for you, sir.
-先生們？        -亨德利隊長...
-Well, gentlemen?    -Capt. Hendry...
-對不起，博士。我可以？     -當然
-Excuse me, doctor. May I?    -Certainly.
關於將身體從冰上移出，我想指出...
In relation to removing the body from the ice, I'd like to point out...
...有些生物在死後會復生，但寒冷會摧毀它們
...there are organisms that survive after death, but cold can destroy them.
-有鑑於此...        -我不知道...
-In view of that...    -I don't know...
但這些生物很危險，可能攜帶著外星細菌
But these organisms may be dangerous.
They may be carrying germs from another planet.
-那些無法以醫藥對付的細菌   -謝謝
-Germs we couldn't cope with medically.   -Thank you.
-查普曼博士，我無法認同  -我也不同意
-I can't agree with you, Dr. Chapman.   -I don't either.
另一個是：未知這個生物的遺骸會對...
Here's another: We don't know what effect the air of our Earth...
...我們的大氣有何影響  -像飛碟一樣化成輕煙？
...may have on this creature's remains.
-Sort of go up in smoke, like the saucer?
-胡說            -這不會太牽強嗎？
-Nonsense.     -Isn't that far-fetched?
-火星人就是如此    -這不會有結論的
-So is a man from Mars.   -We're getting nowhere.
我建議亨德利隊長立刻與他的上級溝通
I suggest that Capt. Hendry communicate with his superior at once.
我老糊塗了。我們應該完成那第一件事
I'm getting senile. We should have done that first thing.
隊長，我很驚訝你在返程時沒試著聯絡將軍
I'm surprised, captain, that you didn't try to reach your general on our way back here.
我們有啊。巴恩斯
We did. Barnes.
我請你的無線電員轉達，接不通，太多干擾
I tried through your radio operator.
Couldn't get through. Too much interference.
-了解了，我道歉，隊長    -沒事的，博士
-I see. My apologies, captain.   -Yes, doctor.
-嗨，隊長       -嗨，特克斯。
-Hi, captain.     -Hi, Tex.
你肯定惹了很多麻煩...
You sure stirred up a lot of trouble...
-我的信息發出了嗎？     -確定
-Did you send out my message?    -Sure did.
-有回復嗎？   -一小時前，能讀一下嗎？
-Get an answer back?
-This came an hour ago. Can you read it?
不，還是你來     -"福格蒂致亨德利：
-No, you'd better.    -"Fogarty to Hendry:
扣留新聞報導，直到空軍總部許可"
Withhold newspaper story until permission from Air Force HQ."
-史考特，聽到了吧   -好嘛，被別人捷足先登了
-There you are, Scotty.
-Fine. Now somebody else will get the story.
"立即從冰裡取得飛行物，必要時以鋁熱彈融冰"
"Remove aircraft from ice at once. Use thermite bombs if necessary to melt ice."
哦，這就是我所喜歡的軍隊，智能爆錶
Oh, that's what I like about the Army.
Smart all the way to the top.
-你鋁熱彈的意外解套了...  -別這樣，繼續
-That lets you off the hook for the thermite...
-Take it easy. Go ahead.
"在我抵達前，建立臨時結構以保護飛行物"
"Erect temporary structure to protect aircraft until my arrival."
這是另一則。幾分鐘前，只得到一部分
Here's another one. Came a few minutes ago. Could only get part of it.
-繼續      -"全部停飛，不能..."
-Go ahead.   -"Everything grounded. Can't..." Something.
-"要你..."某些事...   -聽起來像福格蒂
-"Want you..." Something or other...
-That sounds like Fogarty.
-然後斷線了      -什麼都沒得到？
-Then it got fouled up.   -You're getting nothing?
沒有，被靜電波蓋掉了
Nothing. Static's knocking it right out of the air.
-你的東西呢？  -不知他們拿到了沒，我懷疑
-What about your stuff?
-Don't know if they're getting it. I doubt it.
我不信，連「小馬快遞」都能通過
I don't believe it. Even the Pony Express got through.
-博士？       -鑑於此種新情況...
-Well, doctor?   -In view of this new situation...
-舊規則沒變        -我們無法認同
-Doesn't alter the old one.   -We disagree with you.
-沒有理由拖延...   -各位抱歉了，就這樣
-There's no reason to delay...   -Sorry, gentlemen. That's it.
特克斯，我要巴恩斯留下來盡力幫忙
Tex, I'd like to leave Barnes to help out all he can.
-當然         -巴恩斯，繼續努力搶通
-Sure.    -Barnes, keep trying to get through.
我想向將軍發射一個信息
I wanna get a message to the general.
告訴他飛行物已被鋁熱彈徹底摧毀了
Tell him the aircraft was completely destroyed by the thermite bomb.
-告訴他發現一名乘客...   -火星來的？在哪裡？
-Tell him we found a passenger...
-A fellow from Mars? Where?
在冰上，哥們
On ice, buddy.
告訴他屍體在冰塊裡，卡林頓博士請求...
Tell him the body's in ice and Dr. Carrington wants permission...
...從冰裡取下屍體進行查驗
...to remove the body from the ice for examination.
在進一步行動之前，我們會靜待指示
We're standing by for instructions before further action.
是，長官
Yes, sir.
-要補充嗎，博士？   -有個非常基本的觀點
-You got anything to add, doctor?
-Yes, one very essential point.
我認為進行檢驗非常重要
That I concider it vitally important that the examination be made.
-務必要做，是啊    -加上那個，巴恩斯
-By all means. Yeah.    -Add that, Barnes.
謝謝你，隊長。我只關心這個
Thank you, captain. That's all that concerns me.
李察，一有回應，希望你讓我知道
Richard when you get your answer, I expect you to let me know.
是的，博士
Yes, doctor.
我會去採訪博士對你評價，等著瞧吧
Wait till I interview the doctor about what he thinks of you.
-可能印象不錯吧   -如果不是，我會留情
-Probably pretty good.   -If it isn't, I'll make it good.
特克斯，繼續努力
巴恩斯，如果接通，順便問史考特先生的事
Tex, keep trying. Barnes, if he gets through,
ask the general again about clearing Mr. Scott.
別想討好我，我不會更喜歡你
Don't try to soft-soap me. I don't like you any better.
艾迪，我陪你吃飯    -我會拿一些吃的
-I'll eat with you, Eddie.   -I'll send you some chow.
什麼事，鮑伯？
What is it, Bob?
就是麥克弗森中尉看守冰塊裡的那傢伙
It's about Lt. McPherson sitting in there with that thing in the block of ice.
變得很緊張？
Getting nervous?
他不要我告訴你，長官，但他心慌意亂
Well, he wouldn't want me to tell you, sir, but he's having kittens.
雷興堡之役以後，沒聽過他會這樣尖叫
I haven't heard him squawk like this since Rechenberg.
真的？
Really?
長官，冰塊逐漸透明，那東西清晰可見
You see, sir, the ice is clearing up,
and we can see that thing pretty good now.
瘋狂的手，光頭，還有眼睛...
It's got crazy hands and no hair, and the eyes...
-是張開的，好像可以看到你  -鮑伯，我沒聽過你...
-They're open and look like they can see.
-Bob, I haven't heard you...
長官，也嚇到我了，我沒在那裡待太久
It's got me too, sir, and I wasn't in there very long.
-此外相當冷。我給了中尉電熱毯  -好
Besides that, it's pretty cold. I got the lieutenant an electric blanket.
-Good
-隊長，我有個建議      -說吧
-Captain, I got a suggestion.   -Go ahead.
不要四小時輪班，可以再減一半...
Instead of four-hour shifts, we could cut them in half...
好，你叫巴恩斯2200去接替
Okay. You tell Barnes to take over at 2200.
你接管2400，我會在0200去接替你
You take over at 2400, and I'll relieve you at 0200.
-我想你是對的，長官    -我認為你是
-I think you're right, sir.   -I think you are.
謝謝你，長官
Thank you, sir.
帕特，巴恩斯剛來過，真高興不用再看那東西了
Hi, Pat. Barnes just got here.
Sure glad I'm not looking at that guy anymore.
-全弄好了，巴恩斯？   -是，長官
-All set, Barnes?   -Yes, sir.
-帶件電子飛行服和咖啡   -鮑伯2400來接替
-Got an electric flying suit and coffee.
-Bob will relieve you at 2400.
-別緊張        -是啊
-Take it easy.       -Yeah.
好多了
That's better.
亨德利隊長！亨德利隊長！亨德利隊長
Capt. Hendry! Capt. Hendry! Capt. Hendry.
什麼事，下士？
What's the matter, corporal?
隊長呢？我得告訴他那東西還活著。我看到了
Where's the captain?
I've got to tell him that thing's alive. I saw it.
它追我。它沒死。它...
It chased me. It's not dead. It's...
亨德利隊長！
Capt. Hendry!
長官，那東西還活著。我開槍打中了它
That thing's alive, sir. I saw it. I shot at it. I hit it, I know it.
但沒有用，它一直逼近我，還發出喵喵叫聲音
Nothing happened. It kept coming at me, making a noise like a cat meowing.
如果你看見那雙手和那雙眼睛！你必須採取...
If you could have seen those hands and those eyes! You've got to do something...
麥克，鮑伯，去拿槍來。巴恩斯，發生了什麼？
Mac, Bob, get some guns. Now, Barnes, what happened?
對不起，不是很清楚 但突然活過來，並逼近我
I'm sorry, sir. I don't know exactly, but all of a sudden it was alive and coming at me.
我開槍擊中它，一點也沒用，所以我跑了...
I shot at it and hit it. Nothing happened, so I ran...
-慢慢來            -對不起，長官
-Easy, easy.       -I'm sorry, sir.
-槍，隊長        -好好照顧他好嗎？
-Here, captain.   -Take care of him. Will you?
回去睡覺
Get back to sleep.
跟其他人一起後退
Get back with the rest of them.
-是什麼...？   -奇德說他還活著。我相信
-What could've...?   -Kid said he was alive. I believe him.
我就知道。在那裡時，我都能感受到
I knew it. All the time I was here, I could feel it.
原來是這樣，電毯是開著的。還是溫的
Here's what did it. This blanket was on. It's still warm.
-他走了沒錯   -去拿皮大衣，靴子和手電筒！
-He got out of here, all right.
-Get parkas, boots and a flashlight!
-聽，狗狗會把他撕成碎片  -我們必須救他
-Listen. They'll tear him to pieces.   -We must save him.
慢著，博士。五分鐘內凍死你，動動腦子！
Hold it, doctor. You'll freeze to death in five minutes. Use your head!
-希望你是對的，我緊張過度了
-I expect you're right. I was overanxious.
從這裡看，隊長！
Look over here, captain!
-你們的東西應該都拿來了
-I think I've got yours.
可以給我一個嗎，隊長？
May I have one, captain?
博士，還是我們去吧
Better let us go, doctor.
-醫生，能看到什麼嗎？    -不多
-Doc, can you see anything out there?   -Not much.
-都準備好了嗎？      -開門
-You all set?     -Let her go.
隊長，如果你們任何人能描述
你在外頭看到的東西，會大有幫助
Captain, it would help if you, any of you,
would describe what you saw out there.
太冷了看的不清楚，但狗把他撲倒了
It was too cold to see well, but the dogs had him down.
-站來時三隻狗掛在臂上   -他甩掉一隻
-He got up with three hanging on his arm.
-He threw one at the rest.
-兩隻死了    -看起來像被絞肉機絞過
-Two were dead.   -Looked like they'd been through a chopper.
-在哪裡找到手臂？    -一部分被狗壓住
-Where did you find the arm?   -Partly under one of them.
狗可以撕下一隻胳膊嗎？
Could dogs tear off an arm?
這種手臂
This kind of an arm.
-小心，倒鉤很鋒利   -似乎是某種角質體
-Be careful, doctor. Those barbs are sharp.
-Seems to be a sort of chitinous substance.
別掉文
Speak English.
介於甲蟲的背殼和玫瑰刺之間的東西
Something between a beetle's back and a rose thorn.
-長刺的手指？       -強壯異常
-Thorn-fingered?    -Amazingly strong.
-非常有效的武器         -非常
-Very effective as a weapon.   -Very.
用不著憂心，斷了一臂又那麼冷，他活不了
We don't have to worry about that.
An arm off and out in that cold, he's dead now.
在一大塊冰裡待了24小時而安然無恙
Got along fine in a block of ice for 24 hours.
-12隻狗攻擊他，身手真敏捷  -失去了一臂
-Pretty spry for a guy with 12 dogs on him.
-And for losing an arm.
-我卻失去了理智      -很驚人，不是嗎？
-I'm losing my mind.   -Amazing, isn't it?
-驚人的強壯           -怪異
-Amazingly strong.    -Strange.
-我敢肯定     -手上有鮮血，不是嗎？
-I'm sure of it.   -That is blood on the hand. Isn't it?
-對，但不是他的       -可能是狗血
-Yes, but not his.   -Probably from one of the dogs.
手臂上沒血，也沒有動物組織
There's no blood in the arm, no animal tissue.
史登博士，能在顯微鏡下看一下嗎？
Dr. Stern, would you have a look at this under the microscope?
不，史考特先生。我很懷疑它是否會死...
就是我們所理解的死亡
No, Mr. Scott. I doubt very much if it can die, as we understand dying.
-老天！            -是
-Holy cat!      -Yes.
博士，那麼？
Well, doctor?
沒有顯示動脈結構，看不到神經末梢
No arterial structure indicated. No nerve endings visible.
多孔的，支離破碎的細胞生長
Porous, unconnected cellular growth.
等等，博士。你好像在描述一種蔬菜
Just a minute, doctor. Sounds like you're trying to describe a vegetable.
-就是啊，你都了解了嗎？   -哦，天啊！
-I am. Are you getting all of this?  -Oh, for Pete's sake!
博士，所以巴恩斯士官的子彈沒作用
You know, doctor, that could be why Sgt. Barnes' bullets had no effect.
-那就對了    -只在蔬菜上挖幾個洞罷了
-That's right.   -Merely holes drilled into vegetable matter.
這裡有綠色液體
This green fluid here.
-像植物汁液    -可能會發現裡面有糖基
-Like plant sap.   -We'll probably find it has a sugar base.
拜託，博士，我得問這個問題
Please, doctor, I've got to ask this.
聽起來好像...是某種超級的胡蘿蔔
It sounds like, well... Just as though you're describing some form of super carrot.
史考特先生，幾乎可以這麼說
That's nearly right, Mr. Scott.
這胡蘿蔔 有能力建造飛行數百萬英里...
This carrot, as you call it, has constructed an aircraft capable of flying millions of miles...
...以人類尚未知的能源推動的飛行物
...propelled by a force as yet unknown to us.
-高智能胡蘿蔔，心思難測    -不至於
-An intellectual carrot. The mind boggles.  -It shouldn't.
想像一下，在第三紀這會有多怪異...
Imagine how strange it would have seemed during the Pliocene age...
...能預測滿地爬蠕蟲，魚類，蜥蜴會進化成人類
...to forecast that worms, fish, lizards that crawled over the Earth would evolve into us.
我們訪客在他們的星球上演化出...
On the planet from which our visitor came...
...蔬菜形式，就如我們演化成動物形式...
...vegetable life underwent an evolution similar to that of our own animal life...
...這正可解釋其大腦的優越性
...which would account for the superiority of its brain.
它的發展不會受到情緒或性因素的影響
Its development was not handicapped by emotional or sexual factors.
卡林頓博士，你得過諾貝爾獎
Dr. Carrington, you won the Nobel Prize.
你已經囊括了科學家們所能獲得的各項榮譽
You've received every kind of kudos a scientist can attain.
如果你待價而沽，我能向外國政府籌資買下你
If you were for sale, I could get a million bucks for you from any foreign government.
我不會貿然地跳出來說你荒誕不經...
I'm not, therefore, gonna stick my neck out and say you're stuffed full...
...滿口胡言。但我保證，我的讀者會這麼認為
...of wild blueberry muffins. But I promise you, my readers are gonna think so.
快不會了。除非他們對自己星球的植物一無所知
Not for long, Mr. Scott. Not if they know anything about the flora of their own planet.
你是說地球上有會思考的蔬菜嗎？
You mean there are vegetables right here on Earth that can think?
某種思考方式，是的。聽過電報藤嗎？
A certain kind of thinking, yes.
You ever hear of the telegraph vine?
-最近沒有         -或者...
-Not recently.     -Or the...
-acanthus世紀的植物，史登博士？  -是
-Is it the acanthus century plant, Dr. Stern?   -Yes.
來吧，博士。那是你的領域
Go ahead, doctor. That's your field.
這植物捕食老鼠，蝙蝠，松鼠等小型哺乳動物
Well, the century plant catches mice, bats, squirrels, any small mammals.
用甜糖漿作誘餌，然後抓住獵物並進食
Uses a sweet syrup as bait, then holds onto its catch and feeds on it.
什麼是電報藤？
What's the telegraph vine?
研究證明，電報藤可以向同一物種發出信號...
The vine, research has proven, can signal to other vines of the same species...
...距離可達20到100英里
...vines 20 to 100 miles away.
史考特先生，植物和蔬菜有智慧已經老掉牙了
Intelligence in plants and vegetables is an old story, Mr. Scott.
歷史比忽視它的傲慢動物還要久
Older even than the animal arrogance that has overlooked it.
-這個給里普利         -看這裡
-That's one for Ripley.    -Look here.
這是我從手掌的軟組織取下來的
I took this from under the soft tissue in the palm of the hand.
-一個莢果              -莢果？
-A seedpod.      -Seedpod?
是的，植物之嚴整不含糊的生殖技術
Yes. The neat and unconfused reproductive technique of vegetation.
沒有我們所知的痛苦或愉悅
No pain or pleasure as we know it.
沒有情緒...
No emotions...
...沒有心思
...no heart.
優於我們，全方位超越我們
Our superior. Our superior in every way.
先生們，你們能理解我們的大發現嗎？
Gentlemen, do you realize what we've found?
來自另一個世界的生物 與我們極端的不同
A being from another world as different from us as one pole from the other.
只要我們能與它溝通...
If we can only communicate with it...
...我們可以學習並揭開人類起源的秘密...
...we can learn secrets that have been hidden from mankind since the beginning...
老天，它在動
Holy cat. It's moving.
-尼克森小姐        -是的，博士？
-Miss Nicholson.     -Yes, doctor?
凌晨12點10分，這隻手活了起來
At 12:10 a.m., the hand became alive.
前臂的溫度升高20度
The temperature of the forearm showed a 20-degree rise.
由於溫度上升，我相信它能夠攝取...
Because of this rise in temperature, I believe it was able to ingest...
...它所覆蓋的犬血，我相信...
...the canine blood with which it was covered. I believe...
你的意思是...你是說它以血液維生
You mean... You mean it lives on blood.
-只能找到這個      -如果這不行，那就沒轍了
-This is the best we could find.
-If doesn't work I don't know what will.
-隊長去哪兒？    -盡可能找到我們的訪客
-Where are you going captain?
-To find our visitor, if we can.
等等，隊長！
One moment, captain!
再檢查一次庫房，所有的外門都上栓
Check the storeroom again. Bolt any outside doors.
隊長，當你找到想找的東西時...
Captain, when you find what you're looking for...
...記住它是身處異地的陌生人
...remember it's a stranger in a strange land.
唯一的罪行是出於自衛
The only crimes were those committed against it.
自冰塊中醒來，受一群狗攻擊 被人槍擊
It woke from a block of ice, was attacked by dogs and shot by a frightened man.
-我只求一個溝通的機會   -關起來後再說吧
-All I want is a chance to communicate with it.
-Fine, provided it's locked up.
如果抓住他，被作成沙拉之前 先讓我拍照
If we catch him, let me take his picture before somebody makes a salad of him.
當然，史考特
Sure, Scotty.
-鮑伯，上那邊     -怎麼回事？像個私刑派對
-Bob, get up on there.
-What's up? Looks like a lynching party.
-有訪客嗎？         -鬼也沒有
-Have any visitors?    -Not a soul.
收到了將軍的部分信息，要暫緩史考特的報導
I got part of a message from the general.
He said to wait on Mr. Scott's story.
還不是白說？反正現在什麼也發不出去
What's the difference? Nothing's going out anyway.
-你在找什麼？       -不可能來這裡
-What are you looking for?   -Couldn't come in here.
-誰？           -火星人
-Who?     -The man from Mars.
你的意思...他還活著嗎？
You mean he's alive and loose?
把門鎖好。有必要就用斧頭，槍沒用
Keep your door locked. Use your axe if you have to. Gun's no good.
你說槍沒用是啥意思？現在...
What do you mean the gun's no good? Now, look...
艾迪
Eddie.
停，隊長。
Hold it, captain.
-這裡有蹊蹺         -你有點離譜
-There's something in here, all right.
-You're a little off base.
那是礦物實驗室，有放射性同位素
That's the mineralogy lab. Radioactive isotopes are in there.
滿屋子的鈾礦石 偵測器當然會有反應
Your Geiger's reacting to a roomful of uranium ore samples.
是啊
Yeah.
-門被鎖住了       -史登博士有鑰匙
-This door's locked.    -Dr. Stern has the key.
-哦，是的       -裡面是什麼？
-Oh, yes.      -What's in here?
溫室，愛斯基摩人受不了草莓的誘惑
The greenhouse. The Eskimos have a weakness for our strawberries.
-北極的草莓           -對不起
-Strawberries at the North Pole.   -Excuse me.
麥克。鮑伯
Mac. Bob.
查看桌底下
Look under these tables.
鮑伯，去檢查門外
Bob, check that outside door.
-門鎖住了，長官       -什麼都沒有
-Door's locked, sir.    -Nothing up here.
還是揮棒落空
We're still batting zero.
-博士？         -隊長，我...
-Well, doctor?     -Captain, I...
其他走廊也沒有     -有建議嗎，博士？
-Nothing up that other corridor.    -Any suggestions, doctor?
-顯然他不在室內     -我們去外面找...
-He's obviously not inside.   -We'll start looking outside...
-請關上門            -算了
-Close the door, please.   -Never mind.
隊長，現在在外面只能撐半小時，輪流比較好
Captain, half an hour outside now is all we can stand. We'd better do it in relay.
-沒錯，查普曼博士。我們會解決... -關上門好嗎？
-You're right, Dr. Chapman. We'll work out...
-Would you close the door, please?
我們得通知福格蒂將軍發生了什麼事
We have to tell General Fogarty what happened.
我們可能會出名
We're liable to become famous.
很少有人會吹噓在同一天內搞丟了飛碟和火星人
So few people can boast they've lost a flying saucer and a man from Mars all in one day.
如果哥倫布發現美洲又走失了 人們會怎麼待他
Wonder what they'd have done to Columbus if he'd discovered America, then mislaid it.
一群笨手笨腳的
Bunch of butterfingers.
先生們，我碰巧注意到...
Gentlemen, I just happened to notice...
看看這些苔蘚
Look at these moss.
它們枯萎了。只有一件事會...
They're wilted. The only thing that could...
如果後門被打開，一陣冰冷的空氣
A blast of icy air if that rear door was opened.
教授，去看看那把鎖         -是
-Have a look at that lock, professor.   -Yes.
-曝露10或15秒就夠了    -確實
-10 or 15 seconds of exposure would do it.    -Exactly.
你的結論是什麼？
What would that lead you to?
可能是...
That it may have been...
-在這裡                -毫無疑問
-In here.      -Without a doubt.
卡林頓博士，你是對的。鎖被重新鎖上
Dr. Carrington, you were right.
The lock's been forced back into position.
鑰匙不見了。有人進來過 離開時在外面...
The key's gone. Someone has entered and gone and locked the door from...
-鎖了門      -瞧瞧它如何迎著光閃閃發亮？
-From the outside.   -Look. See how it glistens in the light?
聞起來像...
It's a smear of...
-植物汁液。來自傷臂？  -你該不會認為...
-Plant sap. From the wounded arm?   -You don't suppose...?
請打開
Open it, please.
-一隻雪橇犬          -還沒變冷
-One of the sled dogs.    -Not even cold yet.
-博士，不會有點...？  -乾癟。那裡有血嗎？
-Doctor, doesn't it seem kind of...?
-Shrunken. Is there any blood in there?
-沒有            -沒血
-None.      -No blood.
-沒血嗎？           -血液已被抽走
-No blood?    -Its blood has been drained.
一切都符合推論
Everything falls right into line.
像這種生物 要在附近找空地 來這裡會奇怪嗎？
What could be more natural for such a being than seeking out the only open earth nearby?
它來這裡避難，聽到我們的聲音就跑了
It came here for refuge, heard us and ran.
-它一直在這，而且會再回來   -最好告訴...
-It's been here. It will come back again.
-We better tell...
我不同意。用科學來處理比軍隊好太多了...
I don't agree. It's far better if science rather than the Army...
-你確定這是最佳選擇？   -我相信可以與之溝通
-Are you sure this is the best thing to do?
-I'm sure we can communicate with it.
它比我們聰明
這是與它交談的唯一機會，可以學到很多東西
It's wiser than we are. It's our only chance to talk to it, to learn so many things.
-卡林頓博士是對的    -你當然明白，史登
-Dr. Carrington is right.   -Surely you understand that, Stern.
今晚你們願意跟我一起在此守候嗎？
Will you two stand guard here with me tonight?
-當然，博士          -很好
-Surely, doctor.       -All right.
史登，告訴奧爾巴赫和奧爾森博士我們的發現
Stern, tell Dr. Auerbach and Dr. Olson what we've found.
請他們早上回來接替我們
Ask them to come back and relieve us in the morning.
請告訴他們，不可向任何人透露
And tell them, please, to confide in no one.
-有斬獲，隊長？ -李，最好多準備一些咖啡
-Any luck, captain?   -Lee, you better get some more coffee ready.
-找到什麼，隊長？     -沒有跡象
-Find anything, captain?    -Not a sign.
巴恩斯撞見一隻北極熊     -確實
-Barnes flushed a polar bear.    -Sure did.
-嚇到你？     -知道是熊就不怕了
-Scare you?    -Not after I saw it was only a bear.
-太冷了        -你沒發現任何東西
-Too cold out there for that.   -You didn't find anything.
我不認為你會，失去的就不會再復回
I didn't think you would. When we lose them, they stay lost.
那也沒有多大差異，無線電沒收到信息
Not that it makes much difference.
Nothing's coming in on the radio.
-特克斯，有消息嗎？   -福格蒂大發脾氣
-Tex, you got something?
-General Fogarty's running a temperature.
10分鐘前還很清晰，然後又斷訊了
This came in clear 10 minutes ago, then it got fouled up again.
"福格蒂致亨德利：
採取一切預防措施，小心保護飛機，直到我抵達"
"Fogarty to Hendry: Take all precautions to preserve aircraft carefully until my arrival."
老話，"對所有機上的屍體採用相同的預防措施
Same to same. "Use same precautions with corpses of any occupants."
還是老話，"轉發飛行物的詳細說明
Same to same. "Forward detailed description of aircraft.
尺寸，大約的重量等，很要緊"
Measurements, approximate weight and so forth. Important."
"福格蒂致亨德利：為什麼沒回應？立即回應"
"Fogarty to Hendry: Why haven't you answered? Want immediate answer."
老話，"無線電不該靜默 參考福格蒂致亨德利信息
Same to same. "Radio silence unnecessary.
Reference message Fogarty to Hendry.
立即回應
Acknowledge immediately.
等待報告，沉默令人不解"
Waiting report. Silence confusing."
還是老話，“回應”
Same to same. "Acknowledge."
-同樣的...      -立即回應
-Same to same...    -Acknowledge at once.
-想必他急需我的報告   -都沒提到我？難以置信
-I gather he wants to hear from me.
-There's nothing for me? I don't believe it.
要升上將軍難道不需...？
How can a man get to be a general without...?
在溫室裡...
In the greenhouse...
看到...
See...
-巴恩斯，去走廊守衛    -拿急救箱來
-Barnes, watch that corridor.   -Bring the first aid kit.
-這是我的工作   -鮑伯，快去警告其他人
-Captain, this is my job.
-Bob, better start warning the rest of camp.
-這裡能廣播嗎？   -左開關可全體廣播
-Does that speaker system work from here?
-Yes. The left switch runs to all rooms.
注意，營地的所有人，將門上閂
Attention, everybody in camp. Bolt your doors.
危險的訪客回來了，得到通知前別走動
Our visitor has returned and is dangerous.
Stay where you are until notified.
請待在原地
Stay where you are.
-慢點，沒事的     -怎麼了，博士？
-Easy. It'll be all right.   -What happened, doctor?
在溫室裡，我正在工作。我沒看到
In the greenhouse, I was working. I couldn't see.
突然一陣冷風，我聽到奧爾森的尖叫
Then a blast of cold air, and I heard Olson scream.
-我轉身時，那東西襲擊我    -繼續
-When I turned, the thing struck at me.   -Go on.
我不記得了，我的頭...我一定摔倒了
I don't remember. My head... I must have fallen.
當我趕到，看到了奧爾森和奧爾巴赫。他們...
When I came to, I saw Olson and Auerbach. They were...
再給他喝一些。去拿斧頭。繼續，博士
Give him some more of that. Get those axes. Go ahead, doctor.
他們倒掛在樑上，死了。喉嚨被切開了
They were both hanging from the beams upside down, dead. Their throats were cut.
-我用爬的...    -你離開時 它在哪兒？
-I crawled...    -Was it there when you left?
我看不到
I couldn't see.
長官，給你    -等等，帕特！我想拍照
-Here you are, sir.   -Wait, Pat! I want to get a picture.
等一下。他可以從外門退出溫室
Wait a minute. He could get out of the greenhouse through the outside door.
-我們可以穿過電機室到那邊  -你倆跟他去
-We can get to it through the generator room.
-You two go with him.
-你是說進去？    -想辦法把門封死
-You mean go in?   -Seal the door with anything you can find.
那更好
That's better.
-慢點，先等他們進去    -帕特，我要拍照
-Easy. Give them time to get in there.
-Pat, I want a picture.
-你回去休息         -別傻了
-You get back with the rest.   -Don't be silly.
-用酒賄賂他       -我請他喝啤酒
-It'll cost you a drink.    -I'll buy him a beer.
-好了嗎，鮑伯？      -還沒，但打開吧
-Ready, Bob?     -No, but go ahead and open it.
拿東西來抵住這扇門，能夠頂住門閂下方！
Get something to prop this door, something short enough to get under this bolt!
-拍到了嗎，史考特？    -沒。門關太快了
-Get your picture, Scotty?
-No. The door wasn't open long enough.
-要我再打開一次嗎？      -不要！
-Want me to open it again?     -No!
-拿一把錘子和一些錐子！  -釘進去好嗎？
-Bring a hammer and some spikes!
-Hit that in, will you?
好了，這樣應該行了
There. That ought to do it.
查普曼博士，您確定沒其他出路？沒窗戶？
Doctor Chapman, you're sure there's no other way out? No windows?
-只有前門和後門       -牆壁堅固嗎？
-Only the front and back doors.   -The walls solid?
-瓦楞鐵皮        -你該不會認為...？
-Corrugated iron.    -You don't think that...?
你發現了一條狗被抽光血，為什麼不報告？
You found a dog in there, bled white by our visitor. Why didn't you report it?
-那沒必要     -讓朋友死去就有必要嗎？
-It wasn't necessary.   -It was necessary to leave friends to die?
我派他們去當守衛...
I posted them as guards...
我查過了。他們像屠體一樣倒掛著。希望你能瞧瞧
I looked in. They're hanging upside down like in a slaughterhouse. Wish you'd seen it.
-我們不做點什麼嗎？     -他們死了
-Can't we do something?   -They're dead.
別讓其他人步入他們的後塵，博士
你被限制行動於你的房間，實驗室和食堂
Let's see nobody joins them. Doctor,
you're limited to your room, lab and the mess hall.
你沒有得到任何授權。沒權利去執行...
You have no authority of any kind. No right to assume...
你還是走吧
You better move along.
我們把後門封住了。如果他想走...
We've got the rear door blocked. If he gets out...
...就必須鑿穿儲油槽和幾噸的雪
...he'll have to dig through oil drums and a couple tons of snow.
-鮑伯，下次瞄準點   -我根本沒時間去想
-Bob, next time raise the sights a little.
-I was too busy to think about that.
我們必須在走廊這裡布哨
We're gonna have to set up a guard here in the corridor.
-兩小時輪哨，徵求志願者   -算我一個
-Two-hour shifts. We'll need volunteers.
-Count me in, captain.
是你召集我們嗎，博士？
You sent for us, doctor?
博士，你說有新消息要給我們
You said you had news for us, doctor.
抱歉，我好累。我未曾闔眼
Sorry. I'm very tired. I haven't slept.
這很難...
It's difficult...
難以啟口
Difficult to talk.
-讀一下我的筆記好嗎，尼克森小姐？
-博士，你需要休息一下
-Will you read my notes, Miss Nicholson?   -Doctor, you need some rest.
是的，我知道，但...
Yes, I know, but...
請朗讀我的筆記
Please read my notes.
"晚上9點，我將斷臂中取出的種子 播種...
"At 9:00 p.m., I placed the seeds taken from the severed hand of X...
...在四英寸的泥土上
...in four inches of earth.
我把泥土飽和的...
I saturated the earth...
我從血庫裡拿兩單位的血漿 與泥土充分混合
I saturated the earth with two units of plasma taken from our blood bank.
溫室中的狗的情況 顯示出血液...
The condition of the dog found in the greenhouse indicated blood...
...是該種子育苗的最主要因素
...was a primal factor in the cultivation of the seeds.
凌晨2點...
At 2:00 a.m...
凌晨2點，第一株芽冒出土壤"
At 2:00 a.m., the first sprouts appeared through the soil."
-五個小時    -是，再加了兩單位血漿
-Five hours.   -Yes. I used another two units of plasma.
凌晨4點，胚芽開始呈現明確的形狀
At 4:00 a.m., the sprouts began to take on definite form.
我總結了...
I came to the conclu...
從你們的表情看，你們不相信我
I see by your faces you don't believe me.
那你自己來判斷吧
Well, you may judge for yourselves.
喔，不。這是不可能的
Oh, no. It isn't possible.
-它自我複製          -速度驚人
-It reproduces itself.    -Amazing speed.
這會加深亨德利隊長的印象
This would bear out Capt. Hendry's impression.
他在溫室看到那生物時，又長出新手臂了
When he saw the creature in the greenhouse, it had grown a new arm.
-在脈動嗎，博士？     -好像在呼吸
-This pulsating, doctor?   -As though they were breathing.
-是，人形植物         -超人類
-Yes. Human plants.     -Superhuman.
-全都靠血漿培育的？    -正是
-All this because of the blood plasma?  -That's correct.
注意這些比較接近血漿源；而這些比較遠
Notice these, closer to the source of the plasma. While these, farther away.
-我們還有多少單位？   -夠了，我希望
-How many units have we?    -Enough, I hope.
威爾遜教授，你想聽一聽它們嗎？
Would you care to listen to them, Professor Wilson?
是的，謝謝。我願意
Yes, thank you. I should.
如何？
Well?
幾乎像一個飢餓的新生兒的哀號
Almost like the wail of a newborn child that's hungry.
-我就是這樣描述的       -博士？
-That's the way I would have described it.   -Doctor?
何事，尼克森小姐？  -你會介意嗎，如果...？
-Yes, Miss Nicholson?   -Would you mind very much if I...?
-我要繼續留著嗎？  -不，去繕打筆記吧
-Will you be needing me anymore?   -No. Just finish typing my notes.
拿來還給我，別讓人看到了
Return them to me. Let no one see them.
博士，我認為想你應該睡個好覺
Doctor, I think you should get some sleep.
有太多事要做
There's too much to do.
-如果你累壞了，就無法好好思慮
-我頭腦還很清楚
-Your mind can't work if you're exhausted.   -My mind's still clear.
不，不是這樣。溫室發生的事你沒想清楚
No, it isn't, doctor.
You aren't thinking of what's happening in the greenhouse.
他在那裡用血液培育種子，就像你一樣
He's growing those seeds in there using blood. Just as you are.
你既已見過 一個生物能夠幹出這種事
想想看，有一千個
You've seen what one creature like that can do. Just imagine a thousand.
-我已經想過了           -亞瑟...
-I have imagined it.    -Arthur...
...如果那飛形物來地球 不僅僅是來拜訪...
...what if that aircraft came not just to visit the Earth...
...而是要征服呢？培養某種可怕的軍隊？
...but to conquer it? To start growing some kind of horrible army?
-以人類為食嗎？    -威脅我們的事太多了...
-To turn the human race into food for it?
-Many things threaten our world...
...新星，彗星撞擊...   -但那些是理論
...new stars, comets shooting...  -But those are theories.
-而這是現行的敵人   -科學界沒有敵人...
-This is an enemy here.
-There are no enemies in science...
...只有研究的現象，我們正在研究一個
...only phenomena to study. We are studying one.
進來吧
Come in.
-帕特       -妮基，我想問你一件事
-Hello, Pat.   -Hi. Nikki, I want to ask you something.
最近有人受傷嗎？被槍傷，刺傷或動手術？
Has anybody up here been hurt lately?
Anybody shot, stabbed or operated on?
沒有，溫室裡那東西是第一個轉診病人
No. That what-is-it in the greenhouse has been our first diversion.
兩個月前我帶來了35單位血漿，哪裡去了？
I brought up 35 units of blood plasma two months ago. What's become of it?
-為什麼想知道？  -怎不給史登博士輸血？
-Why do you want to know?
-Why are they not giving it to Dr. Stern?
他們不用血漿，反而要兩個人去捐血
They're giving him blood transfusions instead of plasma. Two live donors.
妮基，卡林頓拿35單位的血漿去做什麼？
What's Carrington doing with 35 units of blood plasma, Niki?
我想...
I guess...
你最好在我下巴揮一拳 再去看看那筆記
I guess you'd better take a swing at my chin and have a look at those notes.
我應該設法阻止你的
I should be trying to stop you.
原來他一直都在這麼幹
So that's what he's been doing.
謝了，謝謝你沒阻止我
Thanks. Thanks for not stopping me.
帕特，提醒你一下好嗎？他累了
Pat, would you remember something? He's tired.
你發現那東西以後，他沒睡過覺而思慮不清
He hasn't slept since you found that thing. And he's not thinking right.
我了解他，他的思維模式跟我們不同
I know him. And he doesn't think the way we do anyway.
但發現了人類無法理解的東西時
他會很執著想解開謎題，他...
But he's found something no one can understand. Until he can solve it, he'Il...
-就像一個孩子有了新玩具...  -這玩具會咬人
-You know, like a kid with a new toy...
-Only this toy's liable to bite him.
再次感謝
Thanks again.
卡林頓博士在哪裡？
Where's Dr. Carrington?
對不起，我沒有被授權給你...
I'm sorry. I have no authorization to give you any...
-我很忙      -我知道你很忙，博士
-I'm very busy.    -I know you're busy, doctor.
我知道你一直在搞園藝，它們在哪？
I understand you've been gardening. Where are they?
-幹嘛？      -育嬰室往這邊走，帕特
-Why?     -This way to the nursery, Pat.
我不能容忍實驗室被人硬闖，別碰
I don't tolerate intrusions into my laboratory. Don't touch.
這就是你和同事在溫室裡搞的東西
This is what your colleagues are doing in the greenhouse.
-這是得寸進尺  -發生那件事 不是我的錯
-This is an improvement.   -What happened was not my fault.
我們看過你的筆記了，你應該跟我們商量
We've read your notes. You should have consulted us.
我人手夠了，而你的看法沒被採納
I have the help I need. Your opinion has not been asked.
隊長採納了，我已給他建議，我可以重說一次
It has by Capt. Hendry. And I've given it to him. I'll repeat it for you.
我們面臨著一些無法預測的危險
We're facing something unpredictably dangerous.
溫室中的生物 很顯然正在複製自己
The creature in the greenhouse is obviously multiplying itself.
我們無法得知有多少
We have no way of finding out how much.
它需要更多的血，而且會設法去滿足它的需求
It will need more blood and will try to obtain what it needs.
-它被監禁而無害   -你怎能確保我們的安全？
-It's imprisoned and harmless.
-How can you be sure of our safety?
或是全世界的安危？
Or the safety of the world?
想想一千個這樣的生物。 一萬個
必須摧毀它，連帶這些子孫
Think of 1000 such creatures. 10,000.
It must be destroyed, this progeny with it.
-不              -我們可以用燒的
-No.      -We can burn these.
-溫室裡的東西呢？   -你像驚慌的男孩
-What about that thing in the greenhouse?    -You're like frightened boys.
-說對了，我很害怕   -任何毀損都是暴行...
-You're right. I am frightened.
-Any destruction would be an outrage...
...對科學的背叛      -也許吧
...a betrayal of science.    -It may be.
-但如果能除掉它，我會睡得安穩
-隊長，巴恩斯終於...
-But I'll sleep better if we get rid of it.
-Captain, Barnes finally...
...發出了一則訊息，這是回應
...got a message through. Here's the answer.
-繼續           -"福格蒂致亨德利：
-Go ahead.      -"Fogarty to Hendry:
卡林頓通知我火星人還活著 讓它活著並保護它免受傷害
Carrington informs me Martian alive.
Keep it alive and protect it against injury.
在我到之前，在任何情況下都不許採取抗命的行動"
Under no circumstances take action against it until my arrival."
你接到命令了，隊長。我認為他們英明睿智
You have your orders, Capt. Hendry.
I consider them sane and intelligent.
-特克斯，我呢？   -什麼都沒有，史考特
-But, Tex, what about me?   -Not a thing, Scotty.
-要怎麼辦，帕特？ -設法改變陸軍的想法
-What do we do, Pat?   -Try changing the Army's mind.
嘿!嘿，是我，艾迪！
Hey! Hey, it's me, Eddie!
-你們進來幹嘛？     -我們撐不住了
-What are you doing here?   -We can't take it out there.
打消在外面守衛的念頭吧
Drop the idea of guarding from the outside.
風太強了，你看不到東西
The wind's blowing so hard you can't see.
它能穿牆就像進門一樣簡單
It can go through walls as easy as doors.
-他怎麼穿過鐵皮牆？    -用開罐器呀
-How could it get through iron walls?   -Use a can opener.
-我們撤離外面的守衛   -把那手放入冰水
-We're dropping the outside guard.   -Put that hand in some ice water.
-誰在外面走廊？  -史東和威爾遜，長官
-Who's out in the corridor?   -Stone and Wilson, sir.
巴恩斯，他們是唯一的衛哨，要他們小心
Barnes, tell them they're the only ones on guard. Tell them to watch it.
-特克斯？       -我在這
-Tex?     -Here I am.
這裡不宜久留，我們撤離了外線衛哨
You won't be very long. We're dropping the outside guard.
快跟其他人進入食堂
Come join the rest of them in the mess hall.
我沒事的，門抵妥了，而且沒有外部窗戶
I'll be all right. I've got the door braced,
and there's no outside windows.
好，你想當勇士也行
All right. If you want to be brave.
-那麼         -帕特，接下來呢？
-Well.    -Pat, what are we gonna do?
這裡有人想要咖啡嗎？
Anybody around here want some coffee?
沒有，但進來沒關係
No, but you can come in.
這是我的藉口，我希望你們會叫我進來
That's the reason I brought it. I was hoping you might ask me in.
-誰想要一些？    -我可以喝掉一半
-Who wants some?     -I could use a half.
-你在說什麼，史考特？  -我在想...夠了，謝謝
-What were you saying, Scotty?
-I was wondering... That's enough. Thanks.
如果我們這位朋友覺得寂寞 到處遊蕩
最後停留此處，會發生什麼事？
What happens if our boyfriend gets lonely and strolls around and ends up in here?
-我一直想了解      -什麼都傷不了它
-I've been figuring that.    -Nothing hurts it.
-你會怎麼料理蔬菜？     -煮了呀
-What do you do with a vegetable?   -Boil it.
-你說什麼？      -煎 煮 炒 炸
-What'd you say?   -Boil it. Stew it. Bake it. Fry it.
-有道理             -它不怕冷
-That makes sense.   -Cold doesn't bother it.
也許卡林頓博士會請它爬進湯鍋
Maybe Dr. Carrington will ask it to crawl into a boiler.
-也許你能借到一部火焰噴射器
-隊長，我有一個瘋狂的想法
-Maybe you could borrow a flamethrower.   -Captain, I got a crazy idea.
我們有很多煤油，我們可以...
We got lots of kerosene and we could...
-點三。點四     -這是我們燒菜的地方
-Point three. Point four.   -Here's where we start cooking.
點五。點六。
Point five. Point six.
那東西走出溫室了。待在一起
That thing's out of the greenhouse. Stay together.
點九。把煤油扔在它身上，然後放火燒如何？
Point nine. What about throwing kerosene on it and setting it on fire?
-不妨試試         -這裡有一整罐
-We can try.      -Here's a full can.
我來拿。我們需要找東西來裝
I'll take it. We'll need something to put it in.
-這有桶子          -另一個桶子
-Here's a pail.     -Here's another.
-一點二           -再去找一個
-One point two.      -We need one more.
-帕特，可以用這個     -好
-Pat, this one will work all right.    -Good.
小心香煙，中尉
Watch that cigarette, lieutenant.
我們要怎樣點火，鑽木取火？
How we gonna set it on fire, rub sticks together?
-我背包裡有信號槍      -我去拿
-There's a Veri pistol in my bag.   -I'll get it.
它一進來，你就潑油。麥克，發射準一點
If it comes in, you wet it down. Mac, touch it off. And don't miss.
-如果需要更多油，你要準備好    -你是對的
-You be ready if it needs more.    -You're right.
-閉嘴        -現在一點三了
-Shut up.     -One point three now.
-你知道怎麼開槍嗎？   -我在電影看過
-You know how to shoot that?   -I saw Gary Cooper in Sergeant York.
-一點四         -過來，躲在角落
-One point four.   -Come here. Get in the corner.
拿這個檔在面前，待在電燈開關旁
Hold this in front of you. Stay by the light switch.
一點五。一點六
One point five. One point six.
-那是什麼？      -聽起來像是窗戶
-What was that?    -It sounded like a window.
-一點八            -關掉那些燈
-One point eight.    -Turn off those lights.
一點九。到了
One point nine. The needle's hit the top.
-快滅火！           -我在滅啊！
-Put the fire out!    -I am!
小心，隊長！
Watch it, captain!
-堵住那窗戶！       -嘿，史考特！
-Block that window!    -Hey, Scotty!
-這會讓你的手舒服點      -謝謝
-This will make your hand feel better.   -Thank you.
-煤油應該夠了       -快準備好
-This ought to be enough kerosene.   -Get it ready.
-怎麼樣，巴恩斯？     -沒有大礙
-How's it coming, Barnes?    -It'll be okay.
讓我生氣的是他沒有這樣做*
我把它摔倒在舖位上
What makes me mad is he didn't do it.
I busted it falling over the bunk.
聽著，我們希望你們都待在這裡
Listen, we want you all to stay here.
我們找到了解決之道，卻燒毀了一間房
We found a way to fight this thing, but burned out a room.
-看它起飛的樣子 傷不太重  -頂多與熱腳一樣*
-It's not hurt much, from the way it took off.
-About as much effect as a hot foot.
它一定會回來
It's sure to come back.
我們不想把這裡全燒了，因此要去追補它
We don't want to burn the whole place. So we're going after it.
它可能去了溫室，就從那裡開始
It probably went to the greenhouse. We'll start there.
同時，留在這裡。看守進入穿堂的門
Meantime, stay here. Watch the door into the hallway.
-隨時監看蓋格偵測器    -滅火器在這裡
-Keep your eye on the Geiger counter.
-Here are the fire extinguishers.
-誰是電子專家？   -這是我的專長
-Who's your electrical expert?   -That's my line.
-你能掛進對講機系統嗎？
-在任何房間都能取得
-Can you hook into the intercom system?
-We can take one from any room.
-我能幫忙    -麥克，我們會在無線電室
-I can help.   -Mac, we'll be in the radio room.
準備好了就通知我們。你沒事吧？
Let us know when you're ready. You all right?
是啊，我想跟去      -你還不過癮嗎？
-Yeah. I'd like to tag along.   -Haven't you had enough?
如果我再點燃大火，誰來滅火？
If I start burning up again, who'll put out the fire?
對於隊長 我們相當感到自豪
We're very proud of our captain.
放一個對講機在這裡，就能照應到這一邊了
Now, look, put one of the intercoms here. That'll take care of this end.
另一個放在交界處，看看是否通到食堂
Put another down here at the junction.
See if they work through the mess hall.
你說你會再使用煤油
You said you were gonna use kerosene again.
-有更好的東西嗎？  -怎麼不用電更熱？
-Know anything better?
-Something hotter. Why not use electricity?
-用你們的照明系統？  -不，連接新的變壓器
-You mean your lighting system?
-No, we can hook in a new transformer.
-會提供很大的電流    -燒他夠用嗎？
-It will give us plenty of amps.  -Enough to burn him?
-綽綽有餘      -兩個電極能用鉛嗎？
-More than enough.  -Could you use leads to two poles?
-如果你隔離電極     -聽起來不錯
-If you insulate the poles.   -Sounds good.
鮑伯，協助他。快，特克斯。上工了
Bob, give him a hand. Come on, Tex. You go to work.
可以的話，接通安克拉治。告訴他們整個故事
Get Anchorage if you can. Tell them the whole story.
說我們狀況不佳，帶上手榴彈，迫擊砲...
Tell them we're in bad shape and to bring hand grenades, mortars...
...火焰噴射器，任何東西
...flamethrowers, anything.
告訴他們如果我不能發送新聞，我開槍自戕
Tell them if I don't send a story, I'm gonna shoot myself.
-先去梳頭吧        -哪還有頭髮？
-Better comb your hair first.   -What hair?
-嘿，再說一次   -哦，妮基，不會你也
-Hey, say that again.   -Oh, Nikki, not you too.
-他很敏感          -你也是
-He's sensitive.    -You too.
-我有頭髮      -那不會讓你更漂亮
-I got hair.    -Doesn't make you prettier.
不，你的呼氣(口臭)      -對不起
-No, your breath.   -I'm sorry.
-他對此也很敏感      -我很沮喪
-He's sensitive about that too.   -I've been upset.
-傻瓜。瞧，我是說這個   -嘿，你也是
-You ninnies. Look. That's what I mean.  -Hey, look. You too.
-變冷了       -一定是暖氣被關掉了
-It's getting cold.   -The heat must be off.
被關閉了
It is off.
沒油了。看看大廳那邊是否一樣
It's not getting oil. See if it's the same across the hall.
-特克斯，電暖器從哪裡供油？ -正後方，外面
-Tex, where do these heaters get oil?
-Around behind. Outside.
-帕特，食堂裡暖氣也關了！    -不
-Pat, heat's off in the mess hall!    -No.
-油沒有繼續進來      -那裡也關了
-No more oil coming in.   -It's off in there too.
-油箱空了嗎？     -前天才填滿
-Could the tank be empty?   -Filled day before yesterday.
主管線被關了，最好去修理一下
The main line could be plugged. Better fix it.
可能會撞上我們的訪客，他正等著你
Probably run into our visitor, who'd be waiting for you.
我們低估了這傢伙
We underestimate this guy.
-試圖凍僵我們，對吧？    -那並不難
-Trying to freeze us out, huh?  -That isn't gonna be hard.
-降到了40度     -外面零下60
-It's down to 40 degrees.   -It's 60 below outside.
-這些房間能保溫多久？    -半小時
-How long will these rooms hold heat?   -Half an hour.
-那時我們就僵硬了   -如果沒人出去...
-By then, we'll be stiff.   -If no one goes out...
...它不會想到其他招式嗎？
...won't it think of something else?
它會想到我們只能靠電力保暖。加熱器，電毯
It'll think that our only chance to keep warm is electricity. Heaters, blankets.
它可以破壞電路，切斷電線，除了源頭之外
It could break the circuit, cut a line, except at the source.
-發電機房      -把大家都帶去那裡
-The generator room.    -Get them all in there.
-我去告訴特克斯   -帶食物，藥品，毯子，衣服
-I'll tell Tex.   -Bring food, medicine, blankets, clothes.
-帶上我們的飛行服
-大部分都燒了，我看看能救回多少
-Bring our flying clothes.
-Most got burned. I'll see what I can salvage.
-把變壓器連接上      -這裡真冷
-Get the transformer hooked up to that.   -It's cold in here.
-那東西把暖氣關了        -什麼？
-The thing's turned the heat off.   -What?
-我們怎麼辦？       -我不知道
-What'll we do?     -I don't know.
接下來就是斷電，所以每個人都在發電機房
The next thing's electricity, so everybody's in the generator room.
外門的防禦工事 你做得還好吧？
Did you do a good job on the outside door?
-胡迪尼也會知難而退    -他會由此進入
-Houdini'd find it tough getting in.   -He'll come through here.
這是唯一的通道；有能承受這種電壓的電纜嗎？
It's the only way. Got any fence wire strong enough for the voltage?
-有一整卷          -這個可行
-Whole rolls of it.    -That'll work.
-什麼？       -鋪在地上
-What?      -Lay it on the ground.
一個在頭頂 還有每邊一個
當它到了定點，就電擊它
A lead overhead and on each side.
When it gets to the spot, juice him.
-我聽不懂          -電線在哪裡？
-I don't get you.    -Where's the wire?
-下面這裡        -那些給我
-Down here.    -Give me those.
-你在做什麼？ -給他安裝一個電動捕蠅器
-What are you doing?   -We'll rig an electric flytrap for him.
怎麼說？
What do you mean?
-史考特，給我一把錘子和釘子  -當然
-Scotty, get me a hammer and nails.   -Sure.
最好讓開
Better get out of the way.
-似乎胸有成竹  -我已經使出渾身解數了
-Looks as if the situation's well in hand.
-I've given all the orders I'm gonna give.
如果我的想像是真的，我會向你求婚
這是你的外套
If I thought that were true, I'd ask you to marry me. Here's your coat.
我想保持開放的態度
I wanna keep my mind open.
-鐵錘和釘子          -在下面
-Hammer and nails.    -Down there.
-要我們做什麼？   -在發電機房，向前走
-Where do you want us?   -In the generator room. Move along.
-抱歉，我改變主意了，全取消了 -大夥兒繼續走
-Sorry, changed my mind. It's all off.   -Keep moving, everybody.
-我想和你再談一下  -沒時間了，走吧
-I want another word with you.  -No time now. Move along.
讓路。清場，把這地方空出來
Make way. Clear this out. Clear this place.
-剪子在哪裡？        -這裡
-Where are those cutters?    -Here.
-你的蓋格偵測器呢？     -我也有一個
-Where's your Geiger counter?    -I got one too.
去會議室。如果找到任何東西，用跑的來
Go to the assembly room. If you get anything, come running.
-給我一雙手套       -用我的
-Get me a pair of gloves.   -Use mine.
-預留要勾住頭頂的線的空間   -還很空
-Leave enough to hook the overhead wire.   -Got plenty.
-在這裡，中尉   -這樣我們就有立足之地了
-Here we are, lieutenant.
-Yeah, that ought to give us a ground.
-沒錯，隊長      -現在降到五度了
-There she is, captain.   -Down to five degrees now.
-很適合滑雪    -史考特，最好穿上膠鞋
-Perfect for skiing.   -Better get rubber boots, Scotty.
-為什麼？     -電力開啟時可以絕緣
-Why?    -Insulation when they turn the juice on.
-對耶            -這裡有一雙
-Oh, yeah.   -There's a pair back here.
-哪裡？        -別忙，你不必穿
-Where?    -Wait. You won't need any boots.
它到來時，去後面。這裡沒你的事
When it comes, go back. You don't belong out here.
我不想參戰，我只想隔岸觀火
I didn't belong at Alamein or Okinawa. I was just kibitzing.
訃聞我也寫的不錯，請忽視我的存在
I also write a very good obituary. Just ignore me, please.
-亨德利隊長         -請說
-Capt. Hendry.    -Go ahead.
這個掛上去吧，看看是否合適
Just hooked this up. Checking if it works.
很好，注意蓋革偵測器
Fine. Watch your Geiger counter.
-麥克，聽得到嗎？  -字字清晰，希望沒漏掉
-Mac, did you hear?   -Every word. I hope that's all I hear.
-我也是    -華盛頓發來了另一則訊息
-So do I.   -Here's another message from Washington.
"盡全力維護生命，但別對你的囚犯採取任何措施"
"Use every means to protect lives, but take no steps against your prisoner."
我們的囚犯
Our prisoner.
-你不能無視命令  -去軍事法庭指證吧
-You can't ignore orders.  -Testify to that at my court-martial.
你在掠奪科學 史無前例的最大秘密
You're robbing science of the greatest secret that's ever come to it.
-回去吧       -知識比生命更重要
-Go back.   -Knowledge is more important than life.
我們生存的唯一理由。去思考，去發掘，去學習
We've only one excuse for existing. To think. To find out. To learn.
除了怎麼死之外，能從中學到什麼？
What can we learn from that, except a way to die?
發生了什麼並不重要
除了我們的思想，其他都不足掛齒
It doesn't matter what happens.
Nothing counts except our thinking.
我們與自然搏鬥，我們分裂原子...
We fought into nature. We've split the atom...
這確實讓世界感到幸福，不是嗎？
That sure made the world happy. Didn't it?
我們在此從容赴義 也沒去破壞智慧之源...
We owe it to the brain of our species to stand here and die...
...乃為全人類的大腦盡義務  -亨德利隊長
...without destroying a source of wisdom.   -Capt. Hendry.
-文明已對我們下了命令    -帶他離開
-Civilization has given us orders.   -Get him out of here.
哦，你們這些笨蛋。你不可能傷害它
Oh, you fools. You'll never hurt it.
-繼續       -蓋革偵測器有反應了
-Go ahead.   -I'm getting a Geiger counter reaction.
-讀數多少？      -點二，但很穩定
-What's your reading?   -Point two, but steady.
盯住，有變化就告訴我們
麥克，你那邊有狀況嗎？
Watch it. Tell us any change. Mac, anything your way?
-一點微光也沒有         -留意
-Not a glimmer.     -Watch it.
這是操作開關
Here's the operating switch.
-怎麼冷的這麼快？   -繼續四處走動
-How can it get cold so quick?   -Keep moving around.
-應該是零度
-現在更低。下一站，零下五度
-It must be zero.   -It was. Next stop, five below.
來吧，火星先生，來拿點優良的蘇格蘭血液吧
百分之百保證精純
Come on, Mr. Martian, and get some nice Scotch blood. One hundred proof.
-給嬰兒喝再好不過了     -叫他別鬧了
-Nothing like it for babies.   -Tell him to cut it out.
不，不。讓他繼續，我喜歡起雞皮疙瘩
這會給我溫暖
No, no. Let him go on. I like goose pimples. They keep me warm.
那東西著火時 你有沒有拍下照片？
Did you get a picture of that thing on fire?
不，我向後倒在床上時拍了一張
No. I shot one while I was falling backward over the bed.
可能只有天花板 和我的大腳丫
Probably got the ceiling and my big feet.
亨德利隊長，有上升一些。現在零點四
Capt. Hendry, going up a little. Point four now.
-等等...麥克，有變化嗎？ -沒變，只是更冷
-Hang on. Mac, any change?   -Just the same. Only colder.
-表示他會經過食堂  -抱歉，我有個主意
-Means he's coming by the mess hall.  -Excuse me. I got an idea.
什麼？再討論看看
What? Here we go again.
那小子很聰明。他見到這些電線會有疑慮
Your boy's pretty smart. He might see these wires and think it over.
-是啊   -如果他遲疑太久，我們就死定了
-Yeah.   -If he thinks too long, we're cold meat.
-假如我們去交會口那兒堵他呢？
-讓他看見我們來追我們？
-What if we met him by the junction?
-Let him see us there and chase us?
光線越少越好
The less light, the better.
關掉這裡和那裡的燈。別說我是對的
Turn off this light and this one here. Don't tell me I'm right.
亨德利隊長，上升了。現在零點八
Capt. Hendry, going up. Point eight now.
-我也有讀數了     -它在這裡現身了
-I'm getting some too.    -It's showing here.
你們兩個快跑回來      -在半路了
-Both of you, back here. Come running.   -Halfway there.
如果加速那台發電機，有更多電力輸出嗎？
If you speed up that generator, can you get more out?
-試試無妨   -比爾和特克斯跟他去。妮基也去
-Certainly do no harm to try.
-Bill and Tex, go with him. Nikki too.
-不行         -祝你好運
-No.     -Good luck to you.
怎麼了？
What's the matter?
-希望我們有測試過  -如果電壓不足怎麼辦？
-I was wishing we'd tested this thing.
-What if we haven't enough voltage?
-在它的雙臂維持擺動*    -一點二
-Keep swinging at its arms.   -One point two.
-它正在走來            -我很擔心
-It's on its way.   -I got a worry.
前線傳來報告，麥克弗森有個隱憂
Report from the front, McPherson has a worry.
-這不是開玩笑          -什麼？
-This is no joke.    -What?
-如果他能看穿我們的心思呢？
-當他接近我時 他會很生氣
-What if he can read our minds?
-He'll be mad when he gets to me.
-一點四          -繼續活動身體
-One point four.   -Keep moving around, you guys.
保持安靜
Keep it quiet.
我還記得第一次採訪死刑
露絲.斯奈德和賈德.格雷(啞鈴謀殺案)
I remember the first execution I ever covered. Ruth Snyder and Judd Grey.
-你拍到照片了嗎？   -沒有。禁止攝影
-Did you get a picture?   -No. They didn't allow cameras.
-一點六點，還在上升   -在他看到我們之前別動
-One point six and going up.   -Don't move till he sees us.
給他機會看到我們。預留時間給我去開電源
Give him a chance to look. Leave me room to reach that switch.
當他觸電時 大家遠離牆壁
Stay away from the walls when he hits the juice.
-每個人都穿膠鞋了？   -是的，長官
-Everybody got rubber boots on?   -Yes, sir.
一點八
One point eight.
我聽到了什麼
I heard something.
快到頂了
It's getting near the top.
各就各位！
Get your posts!
很好，慢慢後退
All right. Ease back.
-什麼...？       -電源已經關閉！
-What the...?    -The juice is off!
卡林頓關了發電機
Carrington's turned off the generator.
鮑伯，帶上手電筒。艾迪，盡可能拖延他
Bob, bring a flashlight. Eddie, hold him off as long as you can.
-小心，他有一把槍     -走開，走開
-Watch out. He's got a gun.   -Keep away. Keep away.
走開，我不會讓你毀滅...
Keep away. I won't allow you to destroy...
打開發電機！退回來，艾迪
Turn on that generator! Get back here, Eddie.
艾迪，回來！離那電線遠一點！
Eddie, get back! Stay away from that wire!
聽著，我是你的朋友。
瞧，我沒有武器。我是你的朋友
Listen I'm your friend. Look I have no weapons. I'm your friend.
你比我更聰明。你一定明白我想告訴你的話
You're wiser than I. You must understand what I'm trying to tell you.
別再前進。他們會殺你。他們認為你會傷害我們
Don't go farther. They'll kill you. They think you'll harm us.
但我想了解你，幫助你。相信我
But I want to know you, to help you. Believe that.
你比地球上的任何人都聰明
You're wiser than anything on earth.
運用這種智慧。請了解我在告訴你什麼
Use that intelligence. Look and know what I'm telling you.
我不是你的敵人。我是一個科學家...
I'm not your enemy. I'm a scientist who's trying...
且慢
Hold it.
長官，等他走進正中央
Wait until he gets right in the middle of it, sir.
隊長，他必須走在棧板上
He's gotta be on that walk, captain.
長官，等他走進正中央
Wait till he gets right in the middle, sir.
-哦，這樣就行了。停，關掉吧
-讓它燒吧 我們不想有任何殘留
-Oh, that's it. Stop. Turn it off.
-Let it go. We don't want any part left.
嗯，現在可以拍照了，史考特
Well, you can get a picture now, Scotty.
-需要一分鐘來預熱        -好的
-This will take a minute to warm up.   -Okay.
現在有什麼理由不讓我發送新聞？
Is there any reason now why I can't send my story?
-只需要五分鐘     -我猜應該沒關係
-Only take five minutes.   -I guess it's okay.
你看起來比以前更帥了
You're looking better to me than you used to.
-全部完成了，帕特      -都沒遺漏嗎？
-All done, Pat.   -Get everything?
卡林頓實驗室和溫室裡的 全都焚毀了
Burned everything in Carrington's lab and the greenhouse.
-那手背也燒了    -卡林頓博士如何？
-Burned the arm too.   -How is Dr. Carrington?
鎖骨骨折，頭痛
He's got a broken collarbone and a headache.
電壓不足
I'm not getting enough voltage.
-我幫你檢查發電機       -好
-I'll check the generator for you.   -Good.
-誰想要一些咖啡？     -不，但你可以進來
-Anybody want some coffee?   -No, but you can come in.
-你最好喝一點，似乎很累  -他應該會很累
-You better have some. You look tired.  -He should look tired.
-他腦子裡有兩件事   -我們只有一個
-He's had two things on his mind.   -We've only had one.
-憂慮結束了，而我們的隊長... -閉嘴
-Our worries are over, while our captain...  -Shut up.
妮基，你能幫忙解決這件事嗎？
Isn't there something you can do about it, Nikki?
我不知道。你知道，北極我已經煩膩了
I don't know. You know, I'm getting pretty fed up with the North Pole.
-隊長有多少薪水？     -不多
-How much does a captain make?   -Not much.
這是一個好的開始。繼續
That's a good start. Go ahead.
-夠養兩個人嗎？    -還差遠呢
-Enough to support two?    -Not nearly.
-隊長，你有飛行津貼  -有些人是各自獨立的
-Captain, you get flight pay.  -Some for each dependent.
-這個好處理    -我不是隨便被擺弄的人
-We can handle that.  -I won't be railroaded into anything.
我有一個主意
I've got an idea.
-一定行得通     -你應該安定下來
-This is gonna work.    -You ought to settle down.
-這就對了     -對我們來說會好很多
-There you are.    -It'd be much better for us.
當然。我們的隊長總是遇到麻煩
Sure. Our captain always getting into trouble.
-記得在檀香山那晚？   -那太糟了
-Remember that night in Honolulu?   -That was pretty bad.
-我不知道他們在說啥  -他是燈不點不亮
-I don't know what they're talking about.
-He should light somewhere.
-你看，他們知道什麼對你最好
-行了，現在電壓夠了
-See, they know what's best for you.
-Here we are. Plenty of voltage now.
安克拉治，北極探險6對呼叫，有聽見嗎？
Anchorage, from Polar Expedition 6. Can you hear me? Over.
-安克拉治，訊號清晰   -按下按鈕說話，史考特
-Anchorage, reception clear. Stand by.
-Press the button and speak, Scotty.
告訴將軍 已經去請亨德利隊長 幾分鐘內會到
Tell General Fogarty we've sent for Capt. Hendry. He'll be here in minutes.
-收到         -那兒有媒體人在嗎？
-Roger. Over.   -Are there any newsmen there? Over.
-這裡到處都是    -好，這是給你的新聞
-The place is full of them. Over.  -All right. Here's your story.
北極，11月3日。奈德.史考特報導
North Pole, November 3rd. Ned Scott reporting.
經過奮戰 人類贏得世上最偉大的戰役之一
One of the world's greatest battles was fought and won by the human race.
只靠少數美國士兵和平民...
A handful of American soldiers and civilians...
...遭遇了來自外星球的首次入侵
...met the first invasion from another planet.
一個叫諾亞的人曾用方舟拯救了我們的世界
A man by the name of Noah once saved our world with an ark of wood.
在這裡，一些人用電弧進行了類似的任務
Here, a few men performed a similar service with an arc of electricity.
降落此處的飛碟及飛行員已被摧毀
A flying saucer, which landed here, and its pilot have been destroyed.
但是，我方力量微薄並非沒有傷亡
But not without casualties among our own meager forces.
我想麥克風交給相關的有功人士...
I'd like to bring to the microphone the men responsible for our success.
但亨德利隊長正出席職責之外的請願活動
But Capt. Hendry is attending to demands over and above the call of duty.
卡林頓博士，科學探險隊的負責人...
Dr. Carrington, leader of the scientific expedition...
...戰鬥中受傷正在復原    -你真厚道
...is recovering from wounds from the battle.
-Good for you.
在我詳述戰鬥細節之前，要給你們一個警告
And now, before giving you the details of the battle, I bring you a warning.
所有聽我的聲音的人...
Every one of you listening to my voice...
...無論他們身在何處，轉告全世界如下：
...tell the world. Tell this to everybody wherever they are:
注視天空上每個角落，持續觀察，不斷監視天空
Watch the skies everywhere. Keep looking. Keep watching the skies.